<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Cars | Ryans Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/categories/cars/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-12T21:31:45-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan J. Geyer]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Have Your Classic, and Drive It Too]]></title>
    <link href="http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2010/06/06/have-your-classic-and-drive-it-too/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2010/06/06/have-your-classic-and-drive-it-too</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I grew up in the 80&rsquo;s, not a terribly exciting time in automobile history.  In addition, my family, while sharing great stories about cool cars in their past, never owned anything particularly exiting while I was a kid.  Maybe the coolest car was the Volvo 145 Estate which we owned when I was very young.</p>

<p>Back then, if you were a car guy you had two options.  An american musclecar with a big block intended only to go from 0-60, or through the traps 1320ft or 660ft away as quickly as possible.  Stopping? Let&rsquo;s not worry about that, shall we?  The other choice was a foreign car, usually japanese, and usually not particularly quick sporty by virtue of the excellent handling and braking abilities.</p>

<p>I started out by going down the musclecar route.  My first car was a 1967 Ford Thunderbird.  It had suicide doors, manual windows, no A/C and the (fairly rare) 428FE engine option.  The original owner was clearly only interested in going fast, in spite of the luxury inherent to the Thunderbird.  I may never know the story of the original owner, but I like to imagine that it belonged to a hip dude with his wife and 1.86 children.  I&rsquo;d like to imagine that the car went to fetch groceries, and surprise an occasional mustang or camaro on it&rsquo;s way.</p>

<p>The car was a lot of fun, and it was a big handful too.  As my first car, with a big block in the front driving two skinny tires in the back I saw the rear of the car pass me more than a few times.  It didn&rsquo;t stop very well, the tie rod ends, rag joint, and steering box were all well worn, so I literally drove it like the hero in the last action b movie you watched.  You know the drill, tossing the wheel about 1/8 of a turn either direction from center rapidly while looking in the rear view nervously.</p>

<p>Sadly, the true muscle car experience was never really meant to be for me.  Since it was my first car, I didn&rsquo;t have a lot of money to spend on it so I didn&rsquo;t repair a lot of the things which were in dire need, and I had no real concept of how to maintain a car like that.  It lasted for a little over a year in my possession before it protested the neglect whilst traveling 105(ish) northbound on the 101 at a little past midnight.  I heard a subtle &ldquo;clunk&rdquo; and a loss of power, and then no matter how far I pushed the pedal down, the car continued to lose power.  Eventually, I stopped, smoke billowing from the engine compartment, and my mind racing trying to figure out how I was going to get home.  Little did I know that I had been being followed for many miles, by the California Highway Patrol.  After keeping me in suspense long enough, the police finally put me out of my misery and let me know that they weren&rsquo;t going to give me a citation, and that the state of my car was punishment enough.</p>

<p>I did manage to get the car apart, and to rebuild the engine, and the transmission.  But then it sat.. For years&hellip; Many other cars came and went, but the Thunderbird sat.  My father finally insisted that I get it out of his shop, so the car got reassembled, but I was newly married, and had arguably less disposable income than I did when I first bought the car.  I sold it for $2500 with surprisingly little remorse.</p>

<p>I also had the small import experience a little later on.  I got sucked into the import culture, and wound up buying a 1989 Honda CRX Si.  This car was quick, and fun.  It wasn&rsquo;t as powerful, visceral as the Thunderbird but it was composed and handled with surgical precision by comparison.  I even got to customize this thing a bit, lowering springs, high performance tires, and a decent high end stereo.  I really enjoyed this car, but I just grew out of it.  Not figuratively, not emotionally, not the fact that I&rsquo;m growing up and it&rsquo;s no longer appropriate.  Nope, around 23ish I actually grew an inch or two, and I simply did not fit in the car anymore.  I sold it, and I still kinda miss it, more than the Thunderbird sometimes, actually.</p>

<p>Neither car was exactly &ldquo;right&rdquo; though.  I really want a car that drives small, and handles well.  But, I really dig the acceleration G forces that can only be generated by a rear wheel drive rig with lots of ponies under the hood.  When I owned the Thunderbird, the thought that it could possibly handle like a small car was not likely.  Not only was it not &ldquo;acceptable&rdquo; to the muscle car purists, but the parts simply didn&rsquo;t exist.</p>

<p>Enter the increasingly popular pro touring car.  Opinions vary on exactly what &ldquo;Pro Touring&rdquo; means but for me it means a synergy of a classic car&rsquo;s undeniable style with all of the conveniences and luxuries that have become standard on modern cars.  Things like a smooth idling fuel injected motor, polyurethane suspension bushings, climate control, cup holders, a modern stereo system.  All of the things that we simply take for granted in our modern performance cars.  The common theme of a lot of pro touring cars you might read about in car magazines is their astronomical price tags, but in my opinion it doesn&rsquo;t need to be that way.</p>

<p>Imagine picking up 60&rsquo;s or 70&rsquo;s coupe (or sedan, no shame in that) that&rsquo;s in good shape.  Chevy, Ford, Mopar, pick your poison but you should be able to pick up a car that doesn&rsquo;t require a whole lot of body work on the cheap.  Since we&rsquo;re planning to put a modern drivetrain in it anyway you could even find a nice rolling chassis that was an abandoned project or a well cared for car who&rsquo;s engine met an untimely demise, and you can save even more cash.  The next step, find a modern engine and transmission.  That doesn&rsquo;t have to be particularly expensive either, your best bet is to find a modern ride that&rsquo;s been wrecked, or spend a few minutes trolling craigslist or eBay.  You should be able to have your pick of fuel injected modern engines with relatively low mileage.  Now, spend some time addressing the little maintenance issues and other small fixes on your classic donor, and stuff that modern drivetrain between the frame rails.  If you play your cards right there&rsquo;s probably some off the shelf parts for your particular swap to ease the effort and cost.  Chances are you&rsquo;ll have spent less than $15k to build a car with all of that classic style, and the reliability and fuel economy of a modern car.  So which would you rather have, a Honda Fit, or a custom classic that you can drive every day?  Yeah I thought so.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android OS CarPC?]]></title>
    <link href="http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2010/05/14/android-os-carpc/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2010/05/14/android-os-carpc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Generally speaking, I don&rsquo;t actively participate in the weekly <a href="http://thecarchat.com/">#carchat</a> on Twitter, but I do occasionally glean a few points as I watch it stream across my Twitter timeline.</p>

<p>Take for instance this week&rsquo;s #carchat where I saw <a href="http://twitter.com/banovsky">@banovsky</a> say the following.
[twitter_status_by_id id=&ldquo;13882824556&rdquo;]</p>

<p>Now, I&rsquo;ve built a CarPC and have some familiarity with the topic, and on the surface this seemed like a REALLY good idea, so I excitedly replied.
[twitter_status_by_id id=&ldquo;13883363838&rdquo;]</p>

<p>And apparently <a href="http://twitter.com/bprosperi">@bprosperi</a> agreed;
[twitter_status_by_id id=&ldquo;13883473947&rdquo;]</p>

<p>Admittedly however, my response was not based on any particular facts or prior research, it just sounded like a novel idea.  So when I was challenged, I honestly didn&rsquo;t have anything particularly intelligent to say.
[twitter_status_by_id id=&ldquo;13883392253&rdquo;]</p>

<p>[twitter_status_by_id id=&ldquo;13883614504&rdquo;]</p>

<p>That was pretty much it for that conversation, I was running out the door to head home from work, and there didn&rsquo;t seem to be a lot of activity on that conversation topic.  But the brief exchange did get me thinking.  I&rsquo;m going to be tackling the challenge of updating my CarPC and installing it in the <a href="http://www.nslms.com/category/cars/1967-cadillac-sedan-deville/">Caddy</a> at some point in the future, and it might make sense to consider my options in the Mobile OS arena.  With that, I decided to refine my understanding a bit.</p>

<p>What I found, was actually quite disappointing!  It seems that a lot of folks in the car computing community have given this topic a lot of consideration, starting all the way back when Android was first announced.  The first several links of <a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=android+carpc">the search</a> I did were all links back to the <a href="http://www.mp3car.com/vbulletin/">mp3car.com forums</a>, and I observed a few common threads.</p>

<h3>Screensize</h3>


<p>Android is hyper focused on small mobile devices (read teeny screens), so while it&rsquo;s very touch centric, which is good for car computing, existing apps will not scale well to the standard 7" car computing touchscreen.  Which means that any software which would be properly useful in a car, on the Android OS, would have to be built exclusively for that purpose.  That seems fine on the surface, but it excludes you from the primary Android market, and creates a new niche which may be extraordinarily small, if it takes off at all.</p>

<h3>Level of interactivity</h3>


<p>Android expects the user to be engaged and actively interacting with the device.  This is a reasonable expectation for a mobile phone that you&rsquo;ll use to play games, use social networking, web browse, etc.  But the car computing use case is VERY different, you want to be able to interact with the device with as little cognitive overhead as possible.  This is the reason that the use of mobile phones is being outlawed in many states.  So again, you&rsquo;d have to build something exclusively for car computing, on a platform with an entirely different focus.</p>

<h3>Pay it back</h3>


<p>Android is based on Linux, but it is not true to the spirit and intent of Free Open Source Software (FOSS).  Android has reinvented the wheel many times over, and created subsystems which do (almost) the same thing as a similar subsystem already available in Linux, but in a way that&rsquo;s only useful on a mobile device.  Fundamentally, this makes sense, since the problems they&rsquo;re trying to solve are rather specific to the application.  The problem though, is that none of that work done to &ldquo;enhance&rdquo; the FOSS software upon which Android is based is of any use to anyone but the Android team.</p>

<p>This problem would be even further compounded if Android OS were used in the context it was brought up by <a href="http://twitter.com/sandbarmark">@sandbarmark</a> for #carchat.
[twitter_status_by_id id=&ldquo;13882779065&rdquo;]</p>

<p>Can you imagine?  Let&rsquo;s suppose GM does decide to adopt the Android OS, and turn it into their own version of Ford&rsquo;s wildly popular <a href="http://www.fordvehicles.com/technology/sync/">Sync</a> entertainment system.  Chances are they&rsquo;re going to take the already very device specific Android OS, take a few key pieces from it, and write their own application suite on top of it.  This would mean MORE duplicated work which would likely prove to be only useful to GM, and not to the Android community at large, or the Linux community to which it owes it&rsquo;s existence!</p>

<h3>My Conclusion</h3>


<p>While at first blush, the idea of an &ldquo;open&rdquo; mobile OS powering in car entertainment devices seemed very attractive I don&rsquo;t think it&rsquo;s the answer.  If GM is going to pursue building some software and hardware for in car entertainment, they should take a serious look at simply building on top of Linux, rather than having to work around the mobile-device-centric limitations of Android.  Plus, if they did it right, the entire Linux community could benefit from their efforts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Explorer]]></title>
    <link href="http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2009/11/09/the-explorer/"/>
    <updated>2009-11-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2009/11/09/the-explorer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I first discovered the Explorer it was in my Spanish class during a video group project presentation we were doing.  One group accidentally left in a part when they were cruising around in their Eddie Bauer Explorer singing along with the Spice Girls, What you Want.  ::chills::  Ewwww.  I thought it was cheesy then when the song was at it&rsquo;s height and it still annoys me to this day.</p>

<p>It was a cute car but it just seemed too trendy for my liking.  I already was starting my love affair with Honda and Toyota.  About this exact time my husband, who I didn&rsquo;t know, was dreaming of owning an Eddie Bauer Explorer, along with a long list of other cars that he would so love to own.  My husband has been a car guy from birth, honest.</p>

<p>I had a good friend that I knew since I was 13 that bought an Explorer after we graduated from culinary school.  She was a personal chef for a family in town and had to do a lot of driving as they had a gourmet pallet and it was her job to keep them happy.  She would drive all over town to get certain items from specialty stores as it was only the best of the best for this family.  One day she got on the free way and didn&rsquo;t see the car in her blind spot till it was too late.  While trying to avoid hitting the other car she spun out of control and rolled the Explorer.  She was hurt but not terribly hurt.  I then was petrified of the vehicle.</p>

<p>By this time I was dating my now husband.  I knew he wanted to own a Explorer one day.  I saw the stats on the news, heard news story after news story about the vehicle being prone to roll overs and how the pillars in the car weren&rsquo;t as strong as they used to be.  Every time the car came up in conversation I would get knots in my stomach and would kindly remind him that he already had two cars and I had my own car.  Why on earth would we want a fourth car?  The topic would be dropped.</p>

<p>Three years later the topic came up again, by then we were married and my husband was in the process of selling his only car.  To be honest the car was too small for my husband, when he hit 45mph in that thing his head would bounce against the roof and it was driving both of us nuts.  He promised that he would be safe in the Explorer, that he would lower it and brought me so many articles about how if you were to drop it by 1 and 3/8" it would be a whole lot safer.  Some of these articles were written by professional drivers and the lowered Explorer was able to compete with some coupe cars in handling.  I finally gave my blessing for him to buy the Explorer.</p>

<p>It was a great car, I even drove it for a while as I was trying to learn how to drive my new to me car which is a stick.  It had great pick up, fantastic storage space.  When I was pregnant and was too big to drive my manual car I drove the Explorer as I didn&rsquo;t have to be too close to the steering wheel.  We brought our baby home in that car.</p>

<p>My husband had made many modifications that made me feel more comfortable with us driving the Explorer on the regular.  The suspension was more responsive, the brakes were incredible, the audio system was AMAZING.  I began to trust the car to keep us all safe when it was dry out.  I noticed that it got scary squirrely in the rain and when the ground was wet.  I would pray that nothing ever happen to my husband or child while in this car, it seriously scared me.</p>

<p>Then one day, I was rushing home as I worked really late.  It had just rained for an hour or more, sudden down pour in April.  I figured I would take a faster route as I was engorged (did you really think I wouldn&rsquo;t mention boobs again?) and was worried about my son having a melt down with my husband.  I lowered the volume of the stereo and headed out.  I kept reminding myself that I needed to be careful, that it just rained for the first time in a long time.  I needed to be aware.</p>

<p>I sat at a red light and saw that it was safe to make a right on to the free way on ramp.  I slowly pressed on the accelerator topped out at 10-15mph when the turn was completed. Then I fish tailed.  I suddenly started chanting to calm down.  I reminded myself not to touch the brake, not to touch the accelerator and no turning the steering wheel because that is how my friend lost complete control of her Explorer years ago.  To just try to let the car coast until I got traction again.  I soon felt the car calm, felt like I was in control again.  I slowly pressed on the accelerator again, got up to 25-30mph and then felt the car begin to spin.  I immediately took my foot of the accelerator and reminded myself not to turn, touch the brakes, not to touch the accelerator again.  When I saw a construction sign directly in front of me I decided it was time to close my eyes, there wasn&rsquo;t much I could do, I just didn&rsquo;t want the accident to be any worse than it was going to be.</p>

<p>I opened my eyes when the car stopped moving.  It was surreal, I wished it to be a terrible dream.  Then I realized that I couldn&rsquo;t get up, I couldn&rsquo;t get of the car on my own.  I was hanging from my seat belt looking at foliage on the median and couldn&rsquo;t find my cell phone.  That is when I screamed, cried, begged for help praying someone saw me and would help me.  I finally found my cell phone and called my husband to get help and to apologize for destroying his baby, his car.  I didn&rsquo;t realize that my blue tooth was still connected to my phone, which I ripped off pissed that I couldn&rsquo;t find my phone.  I couldn&rsquo;t hear my husband answer and not knowing he could hear me I spoke to the good Samaritan that stopped and called 911 for me.</p>

<p>I attempted to call my husband again and all I did was cry, I apologized over and over for screwing up.  I felt like the worst wife ever.  My husband responded the way a husband should, &ldquo;Shut up!  Are you ok?  Where are you?  I love you.  Everything is going to be ok as long as you are ok.&rdquo;  I told every fireman, every police man, and every EMT, every Doctor and nurse I interacted with that night about how I destroyed my husband&rsquo;s dream car.</p>

<p>My husband took care of everything for the next week, he was my knight in shinning armor.  I don&rsquo;t remember him moping or ever telling me bitterly that I destroyed his car.  To be honest, I will be happy if we never own another Explorer, or any other SUV for that matter.  I am happy it was me in that car as I am quite a bit shorter that my husband and I am not sure if he would have been able to walk out of the ER a few hours after being checked out.  I am thrilled my son wasn&rsquo;t in the car with me.  That was my relationship with the Explorer, our break up was dramatic but long lasting.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cars]]></title>
    <link href="http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2009/10/16/cars/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2009/10/16/cars</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/rgeyer/3933790789/" title="family_chariot.jpg by qwikrex, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3489/3933790789_79042eb69d_m.jpg" alt="family_chariot.jpg" class="alignleft"/></a>I have had a great interest in cars for much of my life, it has been a means of freedom to me.  I am a little prejudice when it comes to brands when it comes to vehicles, and you can tell what I prefer by looking at the makes of the cars I have owned in my short life.  I have had a '91 Honda civic, '92 Lexus, and '06 Honda odyssey.</p>




<p>My mother's history of cars haven't been all that grand.  She had an Ford escort when I was little and due to not changing a belt the engine was destroyed, sadly from then on my entire family got a bitter taste in their mouth from that experience.  Then my mom had a four door VW rabbit, while my father drove a GTI.  Mom's car was named Tweetie as it was  yellow and just a sweet little car, while my father's was named Thumper as it was a fast car and when he shifted there was a bit of thumping as he shifted hard and fast.</p>




<p>The next car was a Sunbird and it was a tired, tired car.  My mom bought it from my father's girlfriend at a steal but honestly the mistress of the hour should have paid her to take it off her hands.  I remember the roof was only foam and would shed every time we got into it, and a pen was the shifter.  My mom needed a car, only for a short while as my mother finally left my father and relocated to be closer to her family.</p>




<p>The next family car was a Toyota Corona and I would spend my days sitting in the car pretending to drive, pretend shifting in the driver's seat.  I just imagined driving for a long time and merely stopping to have an adventure where ever the road led me.   Then my mom got an old Honda Accord, and we were all so proud of her.  It was a fantastic car that lasted for 7/8 years, turned out she got the one year of Accord that wasn't that great and when it died, it died.  They didn't release that car in Japan which meant replacement engines were incredibly expensive.</p>




<p>By that time I was figuring out what my next car would be as my '91 civic hatch back simply didn't feel all that adult.  I sold it to my mother for a steal and bought myself my 92 Lexus.  The civic took care of my mom for six months then began to putter and act up then we helped her shop for her current car, a Nissan Sentra.  The husband fixed the civic which was renamed Put-Put as it became my little sister's.  Put put was just traded in for a Accord coupe as my sister was craving more horse power and something with a/c.</p>




<p>That is my current car history, nothing compared to my husbands, but three cars fit me and I love to do the long haul with cars.  I also get emotionally attached so there is no reason to replace or trade cars all that often for me.  I think one of the reasons my husband loves me is because we can talk about cars and have a debate as he is open to almost any and all makes and models, while I tend to lean toward the Japanese cars as they have been fantastic to both myself and my family.  Hey, if it isn't Japanese or German, my family has little to no interest.  Terrible but true.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The X Is Dead.. Long Live the X!!]]></title>
    <link href="http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2009/09/03/the-x-is-dead-long-live-the-x/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2009/09/03/the-x-is-dead-long-live-the-x</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/rgeyer/3885537837/"><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2447/3885537837_5c7f7db8fb_m.jpg" class="alignright" alt="The X behind the van" /></a>
Well, it's finally done.  Today I hauled the last bit of the Explorer to the junk yard.  By this point, all that was left was really the front suspension, the frame, and the shell of the body.  It was not a straight forward experience though, lemme tell you the story.</p>




<p>As you can likely tell from the picture the vehicle was pretty much completely stripped.  The rear axle was also removed, since I have a couple potential buyers for that.  So, I have only the front wheels to roll it on.  Fortunately, a member of the <a href="http://www.explorerforum.com">Explorer Forum</a> came out last weekend and grabbed a few items I had left which were going to be difficult to ship, and brought me a second spare tire, so the front end is rolling on two spares rather than my nice Cobra Replica wheels, which I also have a couple buyers lined up for.</p>




<p>So the question is, how do you move a vehicle that only has wheels on one end?  The easiest answer was to get a two wheel car dolly to stand-in as the rear axle.  Easy, right?  Well it would have been, if there had been any for rent in town!  I started the search yesterday, and called every rental place in town.  None of them had the tow dolly I need.  So, after hours of searching and coping with my own disappointment that I wasn't going to be able to finish this project on schedule, I sucked it up and made an online reservation with U-Haul.  Now, the fine print says that they'll make good on the online reservation no matter what.  So I figured they'd haul one in from nearby or perhaps magically produce one from their bat-cave warehouse.  But, it was not to be only moments later I received a call from the reservation office.  They informed me the equipment I needed was in Santa Maria, some 70ish miles away.  I hymned and hawed for a while, but finally agreed to go pick it up from Santa Maria, and drop it off here.</p>




<p>So today it began, I headed out at 11:30AM since my reservation was at 1PM to pick up the tow dolly.  It was my day to watch Quincy, so of course he came with me.  The drive out was uneventful, made it in just under an hour, and didn't even get stopped for speeding!  Things went smoothly picking up the tow dolly, and I was off in only a few minutes.</p>




<p>So, first things first.  It's time for Quincy and I to eat, or it ain't gonna be a pretty drive home.  <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/rgeyer/3884613841/"><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2675/3884613841_28283a4bbf_m.jpg" alt="Q likes his booster seat!" class="alignleft" /></a>  We don't have Del Taco at home, so whenever I can I seek them out and patronize them.  Quincy was absolutely STOKED to sit in a booster seat, and he ate like a champ (sweet!).  After a quick lunch, we were on out way home.</p>




<p>The drive home was equally uneventful, but much slower.  I just set the cruise at 60MPH and pointed us south.  The drive home took more like 1.5 hours, but I didn't want to find out what happened when/if I exceeded the comfortable speed of the empty trailer.</p>




<p>Got home about 3:40PM and the fun was not yet over.  I had to get the trailer under the X, and get it all strapped down.  That was a bit of an adventure.  Quincy was done with his car seat, so I had to manage him while I jacked up the X and worked to get the trailer under it.  Kinda wished I had another arm right about then.  After some struggling, I got the trailer under the X, and strapped it down with a couple chains, and a pair of nylon straps.</p>




<p>Off to the junkyard at last!  I pulled into <a href="http://www.steel-head.com/">Steel-Head</a> at about a quarter to five.  Cutting it close!  I'd called them yesterday to warn them that this thing is really stripped, and they assured me they'd be happy to take it.  After they saw it though, they were more than a little surprised at just how stripped the vehicle was!  The guy helping me said "Seriously, you did better than my guys do".  This makes me happy.  I love hearing that a project I've taken on has been accomplished at least as well as "the pros".  :-)</p>




<p>The downside of course, is that they realized there wasn't anything they could sell, which they assumed there would be.  As such, I had to pay them to take it which I fortunately anticipated.</p>




<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/rgeyer/3885546261"><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2605/3885546261_5b17c38a78_m.jpg" alt="X last rites" class="alignleft" /></a>After agreeing on the price, the forklift came out, and I started unstrapping the truck.  It had shifted slightly in transit, and one of the chains, which I'd looped over a crossmember and hooked to itself, was completely bound up.  I tried tugging, pushing the truck, everything I could think of.  I was probably at this for about five minutes, battling in vain while the forklift driver waited.  Then it struck me, I'll have the forklift driver push down on the truck, compressing the suspension, and giving me the slack I needed!  I emerged from under the vehicle and took two steps toward the forklift driver when he said "You want me to push it down?".  It's like he read my mind!  In reality, he was probably watching me, laughing, knowing what needed to happen and just waiting for me to realize it.  Whatever the case, our scheme worked, and the X was free moments later!  The picture to the left is the last one of the X.  I learned later, as I was leaving, that the forklift driver was sitting there waiting for me to pull out of the driveway, I was in his way!  You can almost sense the X's despair, as though it's standing before the executioner hoping for a last minute phonecall of repreive.  No such luck this time!</p>




<p>I have to say, there are some mixed emotions.  This is the first real "nice" vehicle I ever owned.  The first vehicle I ever financed and paid off.  The vehicle that my wife and I brought out first baby home in.  The first vehicle I customized to this extent.  Lots of firsts.  But, it's time to move on.  It's been almost exactly five months since my wifes accident, and neighbors were starting to ask questions, and I was growing weary of seeing it in the car port.  Now that it's gone, it's time to move on to bigger and better things.  Namely the <a href="http://www.nslms.com/category/1967-cadillac-sedan-deville/">Caddy</a>.  I'll always have a place in my heart for the X, but I don't think I'm going to miss it terribly.</p>




<p>Here's to you X, you've given me and my family lots of good times.  You've treated us well, and in the worst case scenario you kept one of my most precious possesions safe by sacrificing yourself.  X, rest in peace.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
