<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: videography | Ryans Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/categories/videography/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-17T21:57:49-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan J. Geyer]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Nikon D90 Excites Me]]></title>
    <link href="http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2008/09/17/the-nikon-d90-excites-me/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2008/09/17/the-nikon-d90-excites-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Okay, so it&rsquo;s not news that the new <a href="http://nikonusa.com/Find-Your-Nikon/Product/Digital-SLR/25446/D90.html">Nikon D90</a> digital SLR has been announced.</p>

<p>The camera is the following (new) features crammed into a body with the same footprint as the D80.</p>

<ul>
  <li>12.3MP CMOS sensor</li>
  <li>3 inch screen with "Live View"</li>
  <li>Built in support for GPS geo-tagging in your EXIF data (GPS receiver sold seperately)</li>
  <li>D-Movie mode for up to 5 minutes of 720p video</li>
  <li>Probably some other stuff that escaped my notice or didn't seem important to me</li>
</ul>




<h3>12.3MP CMOS sensor</h3>


<p>No surprise here, it&rsquo;s a higher MP sensor, and is a CMOS sensor rather than a CCD sensor.  To be honest, I&rsquo;m not clear on the differences between the two, but CMOS sensors are what are in all the newer cameras, as well as my HDV camcorder.</p>

<h3>3 inch screen with "Live View"</h3>


<p>You simply can&rsquo;t argue that a bigger screen is better, and the addition of &ldquo;Live View&rdquo; (basically the ability to use the screen as a viewfinder, like your point-and-shoot digicam) is pretty cool too.</p>

<h3>Built in GPS geo-tagging support</h3>


<p>Also pretty cool and allows you to show exactly where photos were taken, though there are ways to do this with some existing dSLR&rsquo;s.  Doesn&rsquo;t really do much for me since I&rsquo;m rarely taking photos in any really exciting places.</p>

<h3>D-Movie mode</h3>


<p>Yup, you can record up to 5 minutes of 720p video with mono sound with the D90.  There is a lot of controversy about this ability, and many are calling it a gimmick.</p>

<p>Now, with all that said, I&rsquo;m not ready to go out and trade my D80 in for one.  &ldquo;But I thought you said you were excited.&rdquo;, I can hear you saying..</p>

<p>Well, yes..  I&rsquo;m very VERY intrigued by the D-Movie mode.  Now, as it&rsquo;s implemented in the D90 I&rsquo;d rather use my Sony HDR-HC1 camcorder to capture video to tape, but the idea of similar resolution captured through a nice Nikon VR lens with the ability to use nice depth of field tricks is very VERY exciting to me.  There have been people who&rsquo;ve speculated that Nikon may make the transition into a full fledged video camera using the technology from this camera.  If they do, and they keep it affordable (say, under $2k), I&rsquo;d be first in line for one!</p>

<p>Meanwhile, I&rsquo;m looking into building an adapter that will allow me to attach my SLR lenses to my little camcorder to get depth of field (DOF), but I&rsquo;d much prefer having something that does this sort of thing by design!</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re curious about the &ldquo;DOF adapter&rdquo;, I just recently discovered that such a thing existed from a <a href="http://strobist.blogspot.com/2008/08/labor-day-weekend-speedlinks.html">labor day post</a> over at <a href="http://www.strobist.blogspot.com/">Strobist</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
