<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Parenting | Random Musings]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/categories/parenting/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-13T18:50:29-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan J. Geyer]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@ryangeyer.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The baby]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/24/the-baby/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/24/the-baby</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/rgeyer/5630016717/" title="Tate by qwikrex, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5307/5630016717_87e53254bb_m.jpg" width="161" height="240" alt="Tate" class="alignright"/></a>
I know I have been talking soooo much about my eldest son, the amazing three year old that has accomplished sooo much in the potty training arena.  I have to say a few things about my baby boy.</p>

<p>I am in awe over this child and know that I will be trying to keep up with him for the rest of my life.  He is a climber.  Like, the kid doesn&rsquo;t walk yet (buries head in sand over the steps he ran and walked randomly) and yet he climbs everything he can get his hands on.  We like to go to a park that has the little play ground and the big play ground.  My baby boy has shown his climbing prowess by climbing the big play ground trying to keep up with his brother that is nearly 2.5 years older than him.</p>

<p>He is amazing.  Oh and he talks.  I am not the delusional parent convinced he speaks well, he is learning and is a great mimic.  He loves to try to enunciate nearly every word that he hears. <em>makes note to clean up the music listened to around him</em>  He is amazing.  Oh and he is an eater.  My first son was only interested in nursing for the first full year of his life.  My second?  He loves to chill at the BF cafe when he can but he also wants a bite of that burger his mom is eating  while nursing him.  Epic.</p>

<p>So he is &lsquo;nearly&rsquo; walking (I&rsquo;m still not willing to say otherwise), he crawls ridiculously fast, he climbs everything he can and I&rsquo;m hoping he loves a diversity of good food, so far so good. :D</p>

<p>I just adore my boys, adore.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Potty Training Day 13:  NO WAY!]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/22/potty-training-day-13-no-way/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/22/potty-training-day-13-no-way</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>He&rsquo;s being all awesome and doing all he can on his own.  I had no idea he would do so well.</p>

<p>I mean I knew he could do it but I had no idea he would just embrace the process so willingly and be so self sufficient.</p>

<p>He is awesome.</p>

<p>I am proud.</p>

<p>I officially have a giant grin on my face so big that even my baby is grinning since that is what you are supposed to do when someone uses the potty correctly.  Yay!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Potty Training Day 12:  Old Hat]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/20/potty-training-day-12-old-hat/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/20/potty-training-day-12-old-hat</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We did the scariest thing ever!  We took both boys grocery shopping while one was diaperless!  Scary stuff, huh?  We went grocery shopping without both boys last week, yes we were big chickens, so what!</p>

<p>My big boy was doing well all day with the potty training, you know acting like he&rsquo;s been doing this for years.  He even had attitude with me when I asked if he needed to use the potty, he rolled his eyes and told me I was silly since he had just peed a few minutes ago.  <em>Epic</em>.</p>

<p>Back to grocery shopping.  We weren&rsquo;t used to this process and both my husband and I spaced on offering a potty break at the first store.  We went to the second store with our eldest son recovering from grocery cart regret, he didn&rsquo;t use the cart with the plastic car on the front per his request to &ldquo;Be like Mommy and Daddy&rdquo;, then lost his mind when he saw another kid riding in it.</p>

<p>So our first trip to a commercial toilet, I was nervous and my son was excited.  We ran to the bathroom since my son announced he had to pee NOW.  I saw the womens bathroom was occupied so I figured having my son with me authorized us to use the mens bathroom.  It worked out nicely and so far my son isn&rsquo;t petrified of those evil automatic flushing toilets.  We did in fact high five after washing our hands and grocery shopping was narrated by my son.</p>

<p>He is just so happy with himself but has this air to him that just says, &lsquo;Yeah, I&rsquo;m just that awesome.&rsquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Potty Training Day 11:  Kicking butt and taking names]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/17/potty-training-day-11-kicking-butt-and-taking-names/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/17/potty-training-day-11-kicking-butt-and-taking-names</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yeah, my son was a rock start today.</p>

<p>He proudly would announce that he used the potty all by himself, with a dance.  Yes, I had to escort him back to the bathroom to wash his hands and wash my own hands since I high fived him with glee before remembering that he can&rsquo;t turn the faucet on by himself.</p>

<p>Yes my son was a potty trained big boy and for the umpteenth time I have realized that my children are growing before my very eyes and it is happening way too fast but this is the wild ride I volunteered for.</p>

<p>For now I&rsquo;m just going to enjoy a song and dance with my son potty training skillZ, yeah with a capital <strong>Z</strong>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Potty Training Day 10: Getting better]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/15/potty-training-day-10-getting-better/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/15/potty-training-day-10-getting-better</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday was horrid, just horrid as everyone was struggling with the emotional turmoil of the accidents.  Yes, even the baby realized that everyone was having a hard time.  It&rsquo;s amazing how your child has an accident and you try to focus all your energy on making it right and yet you, as a mother, find the time to beat yourself up for dropping the ball and possibly not give your kid enough time and attention.</p>

<p>Today, we are getting better, much better.  My son started the day with an accident and a shower and I had a load of laundry to do before doing anything.  We followed it up with being my son then being way too confident with his bladder control and having a moment where he forgot to take his pants off while peeing.  From that point on he was showing his prowess, kicking butt and taking names and kept things dry everywhere but in the potty.</p>

<p>You are so happy you stumbled over this blog right now.  I mean, I can just see the techie followers of my husband wondering what in the hell they came across.  You can thank my ever so wonderful husband for sharing this space with his stay at home mom wife to share the joys of pees and poops and lactating boobies and other fantastical bodily functions.  Go ahead, take a minute to thank him. :-P</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
