<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Random Musings]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-16T09:34:32-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan J. Geyer]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@ryangeyer.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Out of hibernation?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2014/04/13/out-of-hibernation/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-13T18:52:50-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2014/04/13/out-of-hibernation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s been over two years since I&rsquo;ve blogged anything.  That&rsquo;s a looong time.</p>

<p>You may notice that the blog looks a little different (if you can remember over two years ago)
which is because I&rsquo;ve adopted a Jekyll/Octopress based blog platform instead of
dragging Wordpress along.  The result should be a fair bit faster also.</p>

<p>You&rsquo;ll likely also notice that the familiar domain name of &ldquo;nslms.com&rdquo; has been
traded in favor of a much more canonically familiar &ldquo;blog.ryangeyer.com&rdquo;, it should
make me, and my blog a little easier to find.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for more (if I can shake off the lazy).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anatomy Of An Iaas Cloud]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/12/28/anatomy-of-an-iaas-cloud/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-28T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/12/28/anatomy-of-an-iaas-cloud</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>date: 2011-12-28 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>layout: post
title: Anatomy of an IaaS Cloud
comments: true
categories: []
tags: []
status: draft
type: post
published: false
meta:
  <em>headspace_description: &lsquo;&rsquo;
  </em>headspace_page_title: &lsquo;&rsquo;
  Hide OgTags: &lsquo;0&rsquo;
  Hide SexyBookmarks: &lsquo;0&rsquo;
  _edit_last: &lsquo;1&rsquo;</p>

<h2>date: 2011-12-28 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>Multi Tenent for Hardware (KVM, Xen, ESXi)</p>

<p>Ridillin for your Hypervisor (OpenStack, CloudStack, Euca, RAX, AWS)</p>

<p>Unification and Automation (RightScale)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Truth About Set Top Boxes No One Wants You To Know]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/12/19/the-truth-about-set-top-boxes-no-one-wants-you-to-know/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-19T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/12/19/the-truth-about-set-top-boxes-no-one-wants-you-to-know</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>date: 2011-12-19 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>layout: post
title: The truth about set-top boxes no one wants you to know
comments: true
categories: []
tags: []
status: draft
type: post
published: false
meta:
  <em>headspace_description: &lsquo;&rsquo;
  </em>headspace_page_title: &lsquo;&rsquo;
  Hide OgTags: &lsquo;0&rsquo;
  Hide SexyBookmarks: &lsquo;0&rsquo;
  _edit_last: &lsquo;1&rsquo;</p>

<h2>date: 2011-12-19 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>None of them are really full featured, they&rsquo;re all crippled it some way by the content providers that you&rsquo;re really interested in using! :(</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I M Becoming One Of This Moms And It Scares Me]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/11/03/i-m-becoming-one-of-this-moms-and-it-scares-me/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/11/03/i-m-becoming-one-of-this-moms-and-it-scares-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>date: 2011-11-03 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>layout: post
title: I&rsquo;m becoming one of this moms and it scares me
comments: true
categories: []
tags: []
status: draft
type: post
published: false
meta:
  _edit_last: &lsquo;2&rsquo;</p>

<h2>date: 2011-11-03 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;m a fan of letting my children learn and grown on their own in a controlled environment where I can easily jump in and help or correct or protect my children at any given second.  We call it free range children with a side of helicopter parenting.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m attempting to loosen my reigns on my children of late.  I&rsquo;m also trying to do more activities and learning that my chores will be there when I get to them.  We have been making trips to the library so the boys can do structured social time.  Yeah, that&rsquo;s what I tell myself I&rsquo;m doing when we go to story time.  My eldest loves it and gets oh so excited when the Librarian encourages audience activity, it is awesome.  My youngest doesn&rsquo;t quite get the full library ettiquet, but who can blame the 17 month old, seriously.</p>

<p>Today my eldest squealed with excitement during the songs they sing during story time while my youngest kept chanting &ldquo;Bwabwa&rdquo;, brother for baby speak, and demanded that I let him sit with him.  I let him go hovering close by, thinking that the 17 month old may be getting library protocol.  Nope.  No, my baby decided that the circle was merely an theatre for him to show his awesome dance moves which caused the Librarian to get nervous and remind me of story time rules.</p>

<p>This means I got to quickly leap down into the &lsquo;reading well&rsquo; and grab my child who was pissed I interrupted his greatest preformance ever while my big boy hid his face and shushed us as we worked our way out of the &lsquo;reading well&rsquo;.  I&rsquo;m that parent guys, the crazy helicopter parent with free range children.  How will we survive this?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Month One Awesome Month]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/10/30/one-month-one-awesome-month-/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/10/30/one-month-one-awesome-month-</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>date: 2011-10-30 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>layout: post
title: One month!  One awesome month!
comments: true
categories: []
tags: []
status: draft
type: post
published: false
meta:
  Hide OgTags: &lsquo;0&rsquo;
  Hide SexyBookmarks: &lsquo;0&rsquo;
  _edit_last: &lsquo;2&rsquo;</p>

<h2>date: 2011-10-30 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>We have hit the point in the potty training experience where my eldest has deemed potty training fun and he hasn&rsquo;t had a single accident what so ever in a whole month.  One whole month!!!   Know we need to do something extra special for big biggie such a big accomplishment but fir now I&rsquo;m going to bask in his awesomeness.  He is awesome!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Potty Party Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/10/16/potty-party-time/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/10/16/potty-party-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>date: 2011-10-16 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>layout: post
title: Potty party time
comments: true
categories: []
tags: []
status: draft
type: post
published: false
meta:
  _edit_last: &lsquo;2&rsquo;</p>

<h2>date: 2011-10-16 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>It is amazing how much of my world still revolves around the bathroom.  The potty training process began four months ago and yet I have a constant party going on in the bathroom.  I&rsquo;m talking full on cheering, song singing, and dancing occurs on the regular.  I&rsquo;m not quite sure when the potty training party will end as every time either my eldest or I go to the bathroom it become a comical experience.</p>

<p>Things I&rsquo;ve learned in the past few months are:
The empty bathtub is a fantastic place to put a curious one year old while your three year old is using the potty.</p>

<p>Nursery rhymes are the perfect length for hand washing and checking to see if you child has to pee.</p>

<p>Hand washing is fun with three, or at least it is to toddlers.  Personally, I think it&rsquo;s the entire water activity table thing.</p>

<p>There is a fun dance to do even when just drying your hands, don let anyone tell you otherwise.</p>

<p>See, I told you potty training can be party time. :&ndash;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What S In My Bra]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/10/10/what-s-in-my-bra-/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/10/10/what-s-in-my-bra-</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>date: 2011-10-10 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>layout: post
title: What&rsquo;s in my bra?
comments: true
categories: []
tags: []
status: draft
type: post
published: false
meta:
  _edit_last: &lsquo;2&rsquo;</p>

<h2>date: 2011-10-10 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>I have breastfed for some 36 months of life between my two kids.  The end result is I find interesting stuff in my bra on the daily.  So far I&rsquo;ve found:  Cheerios, gold fish crackers, raisins, almonds, granola, cards, kosher salt (my faultnas i foolishly put a small ramikin of it within my baby&rsquo;s reach),and keys to name a few.</p>

<p>The apple sticker had me giggling hysterically in the Victoria Secret dressing room as I attempted to shove my boobs into an overly padded bra that was a cup size too small.  The apple sticker, it was a gala, fluttering slowly to the floor out of my bra added a &ldquo;You are so a mom now&rdquo; vibe to bra shopping I have yet to experience till that moment.  Oh and the overstuffed sausage look when it comes to sexy underwear is not sexy, even when you are shooting for lots of fabulous cleavage.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rs Cloud Dev Best Practices]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/09/28/rs-cloud-dev-best-practices/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/09/28/rs-cloud-dev-best-practices</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>date: 2011-09-28 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>layout: post
title: RS &amp; Cloud Dev best practices
comments: true
categories: []
tags: []
status: draft
type: post
published: false
meta:
  Hide OgTags: &lsquo;0&rsquo;
  Hide SexyBookmarks: &lsquo;0&rsquo;
  <em>headspace_description: &lsquo;&rsquo;
  </em>headspace_page_title: &lsquo;&rsquo;
  _edit_last: &lsquo;1&rsquo;</p>

<h2>date: 2011-09-28 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>I am often asked about best practices for developing, testing and debugging ServerTemplates.  This is my attempt to condense some of the best and most useful bits to make it easier for developers to create and publish some awesome templates.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m going to break this down into two categories.  First will be general guidelines applicable to any ServerTemplate, and the second will be more focused on ServerTemplates which use Chef for configuration management.</p>

<h1>Launch once test many</h1>


<p>One of the early pitfalls I fell victim to was relaunching my server instance for each change to each script when testing.  As you might imagine this practice can be excruciatingly time consuming!  With that in mind here are some tips on how to reduce the time between making a script change and testing it on a running instance.</p>

<h2>Super size me</h2>


<p>Let&rsquo;s face it, bigger is actually better when it comes to instance sizes.  Larger instances are provisioned and boot faster, they run your installation and configuration routines faster and they just generally make your life easier.</p>

<p>I develop a lot for small Amazon EC2 t1.micro instances.  These instances are seriously restricted in terms of CPU capacity and memory.  As a result, simple activities like installing and compiling ruby gems can be very taxing and time consuming.  As a result, I tend to run significantly higher end instances while doing development.  Running a c1.medium in place of a t1.micro (when targetting a 32bit image) results in a lot less waiting while launching and terminating instances and testing configuration.  The added hourly cost of a faster instance should be more than offset by the optimized use of your time.</p>

<p><strong>RS</strong>
Create a dev &amp; prod RepoPath, keep dev at head/master</p>

<p><strong>Any</strong>
Keep instances up and run scripts against them as operational scripts (or equiv).  On RS, use the rs_agent_dev only DL once option and dev/test on the box.</p>

<p>Stop, Don&rsquo;t terminate.</p>

<p>::File, not File</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Time People Thought I Was A Rich Girl And It Was Funny]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/09/15/one-time-people-thought-i-was-a-rich-girl-and-it-was-funny/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/09/15/one-time-people-thought-i-was-a-rich-girl-and-it-was-funny</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>date: 2011-09-15 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>layout: post
title: One time people thought I was a rich girl and it was funny
comments: true
categories: []
tags: []
status: draft
type: post
published: false
meta:
  <em>headspace_description: &lsquo;&rsquo;
  </em>headspace_page_title: &lsquo;&rsquo;
  _edit_last: &lsquo;2&rsquo;</p>

<h2>date: 2011-09-15 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>I am a woman from modest means, I have been for as long as I can remember and it has never bothered me.  My parents were young and never given a hand out of any sort when they decided to marry immediately after high school and start a family.  They weren&rsquo;t shunned but money wasn&rsquo;t handed out.</p>

<p>My life has been modest and I don&rsquo;t think I understood how poor I was as a child until I went through a culinary program at a local city college.  I went in eager to learn, excited to work with all the fancy equipment that I saw on tv.  I went home after the first week completed, eyes wide open and told my mom, &ldquo;We&rsquo;re poor.&rdquo;.</p>

<p>It was amazing how real this words became to me, it wasn&rsquo;t like I was never around those that had more than we did, but I never really cared, I simply figured that was just a different way we were all different.  It wasn&rsquo;t just the magnificent equipment and the amazing amounts of food I was surrounded by in culinary school that let me know I came from a modest home but also the talks about travel I was surrounded by blew my mind.  People around my age, I was only 17 when I started the program, talking about travels to NYC, France, Italy, Spain, all over the globe and it blew me away.  I expected to hear these kinds of stories from my older classmates but not the young ones.</p>

<p>Ironic isn&rsquo;t it?  I spent the majority of my life surrounded by people with means, it was common place for my classmates to flash their newest acquisition in plastic when I was in junior high.  I often rolled my eyes and tried to focus on what I was supposed to be learning.  Yet the gravity of my economic status didn&rsquo;t hit me till I was in college.</p>

<p>The funny part was I guess I was quiet around my classmates in college at first so I was perceived as a snob, and a rich one at that.  People didn&rsquo;t include me in conversations because I didn&rsquo;t get working hard like them, or at least they didn&rsquo;t think so.  Because I was mostly raised in the beautiful town referred to as the &lsquo;American Rivera&rsquo; and wasn&rsquo;t paying exorbadent amounts to rent a closet, and wasn&rsquo;t working while in college; some were convinced I had to come from a great means.  It wasn&rsquo;t until much later that people talked to me and realized quite the opposite.  They found that I was down to earth, friendly, and humble.  I still laugh about the time people thought I was a rich girl.  Though that rep followed me into the work force as the men I worked with in the kitchen teased me as I only had one job while many of them had two, three and one had four jobs.  That rep I accepted because I was a bi</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/08/16/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/08/</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>date: 2011-08-16 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>layout: post
title: &lsquo;&rsquo;
comments: true
categories: []
tags: []
status: draft
type: post
published: false
meta:
  _edit_last: &lsquo;2&rsquo;</p>

<h2>date: 2011-08-16 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>My beloved and I just celebrated out nine year anniversary last month.  I still can&rsquo;t believe that I have been married to my husband for nine years.  I can&rsquo;t believe that we have been in a relationship with each other for ten years.  Where does the time go?</p>

<p>When we met I was only 19, just finished college, just got my driver&rsquo;s license.  My husband was only 20 and dreamy as ever.  Within a couple weeks we were planning our wedding.  Yes, we were one of those sappy couples and shortly after realizing that we really like each other we asked a lot of tough questions like if each one of us wanted kids, how many kids, how to handle money, ect.  When we realized that we were compatible in principles and in what we wanted in life for the long haul, we dreamed and planned.  Then a year later, we were married, blissfully.</p>

<p>Now, nine years after saying I do, we have two wonderful little boys and I do believe that my mister got even more dreamy.  I am thankful for the life we have together, just the four of us and hope for many more years with my beautiful little family.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trying To Stay Interesting]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/08/14/trying-to-stay-interesting/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/08/14/trying-to-stay-interesting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>date: 2011-08-14 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>layout: post
title: Trying to stay interesting
comments: true
categories: []
tags: []
status: draft
type: post
published: false
meta:
  _edit_last: &lsquo;2&rsquo;</p>

<h2>date: 2011-08-14 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>I have been a stay at home mom for a little over a year now and my world seriously revolves around the needs and wants of my children and errands and chores from 8-5 every day, if not longer.  My focus is interacting, teaching, and molding the young minds left in my care until they are grown by my standards.  This includes learning how to play keep the playdoh out of the baby&rsquo;s mouth and out of electronics.  Learning about a huge selection of good music and learning what they prefer.   The result?  This once ever so interesting woman that had interesting things to say is so tired and most of my ideas are hibernating by the time I get a chance to have a real adult conversation.</p>

<p>This means that when my ever so intelligent husband gets home he is often greeted by our adorable boys with open arms and squeals of joy while I take a deep breath and prepare to be a listening ear.  Now, I love and adore my husband and he is an very intelligent man, like bordering on genius intelligent, so there is a degree of preparing myself to hear what he has to say.  When your day is filled with nursery rhymes and instructing your children on what is and is not acceptable, like no, shoving your brother off the couch is not ok even if you feel like he&rsquo;s taking up too much room, my great and hilarious epiphanies have faded in the background.</p>

<p>My husband comes home eager to talk about his day at work, he loves his job, and I am thankful for it.  I seriously make mental notes while he talks about things I could learn more about, I have even been known to google something he has mentioned in passing.  I try to participate but my background is in culinary arts, dental practices, and the very basic HR and management principles while my husband is all about code, security and cloud computing.  We hit a common ground with cars and technology but we are on different plains there too, thankfully there are a slew of other topics we talk about but at the end of the day I am so knee deep in potty training, diaper changing, and all things childcaring related I am just happy to hear an adult talk to me about adult things.</p>

<p>Every day I attempt to watch the news, maybe a documentary, something that is relevant or up to date but it is an attempt.  I fall asleep during the late night news, I&rsquo;m half awake for the early morning news while stealing a little more sleep after nursing my youngest before my eldest wakes up.  I try to watch the evening news while making and serving dinner to my boys.  I look at the news sites both national and local but Lordy that only lasts a few minutes too.  The running joke with my mom about movies or shows we watch streaming is that though I may have &lsquo;watched&rsquo; said thing a couple of times, I have yet to watch it completely.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m trying to stay interesting to myself and that is a feat within it&rsquo;s self.  I&rsquo;m going to do it, I&rsquo;m determined to do it, now if only we could get an extra five hours in a day I would be golden.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Leverage Amazon S Content Delivery Network For Wordpress]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/07/13/how-to-leverage-amazon-s-content-delivery-network-for-wordpress/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/07/13/how-to-leverage-amazon-s-content-delivery-network-for-wordpress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>date: 2011-07-13 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>layout: post
title: How to Leverage Amazon&rsquo;s Content Delivery Network for Wordpress
comments: true
categories:
&ndash; Cloud computing
tags:
&ndash; amazon
&ndash; amazon s3
&ndash; aws
&ndash; cdn
&ndash; content delivery network
status: draft
type: post
published: false
meta:
  _edit_last: &lsquo;1&rsquo;</p>

<h2>date: 2011-07-13 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>For visitors to your blog, one of the biggest factors that contributes to the load time of the page is the static content.  Stuff like pictures, CSS, Javascript files, etc.</p>

<p>One of the best ways you can improve this performance is to serve those things from a Content Delivery Network (CDN).  Follow along as I show you how to configure your Wordpress blog to use Amazon S3 as a CDN for delivering static content!</p>

<!--more-->




<h1>What you&#8217;ll need</h1>


<ul>
    <li>An Amazon AWS account</li>
    <li>The <a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/tantan-s3/">Amazon S3</a> plugin for Wordpress</li>
    <li>The <a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/ossdl-cdn-off-linker/">CDN Offlinker</a> plugin for Wordpress</li>
</ul>


<p>The first step is going to be setting up the S3 bucket where you&rsquo;re going to host your files.</p>

<p>Since we&rsquo;re going to be handing over access to the AWS API for S3 to a Wordpress plugin, we should create a new <a href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/03/28/create-aws-service-accounts-with-iam/">IAM Service Account</a> and set up a <a href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/27/policy-for-an-s3-only-amazon-iam-user/">security policy</a> which restricts that accounts access to only the S3 bucket we setup.</p>

<p>The next thing we want to do is upload all of the content from our /wp-include and /wp-content directories up to the bucket we created.</p>

<p>Make sure to &ldquo;Make Public&rdquo; everything you uploaded.</p>

<p>Once we&rsquo;ve done that, we can go enable our Wordpress plugins.  First enable Amazon S3 plugin.</p>

<p>Wordpress Admin &ndash;> Settings &ndash;> Media &ndash;> Set the path for media</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Motivated]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/07/10/getting-motivated/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/07/10/getting-motivated</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>date: 2011-07-10 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>layout: post
title: Getting Motivated
comments: true
categories:
&ndash; 1967 Cadillac Sedan Deville
tags: []
status: draft
type: post
published: false
meta:
  _edit_last: &lsquo;1&rsquo;</p>

<h2>date: 2011-07-10 00:00:00 -0700</h2>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I Vandalized A Weed Whacker At Home Depot]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/07/02/how-i-vandalized-a-weed-whacker-at-home-depot/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/07/02/how-i-vandalized-a-weed-whacker-at-home-depot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>date: 2011-07-02 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>layout: post
title: How I Vandalized a Weed Whacker at Home Depot
comments: true
categories:
&ndash; Funny
tags:
&ndash; cheap fix
&ndash; diy
&ndash; electric weed whacker
&ndash; home depot
&ndash; screwdriver
&ndash; tool department
&ndash; vandal
&ndash; vandalism
&ndash; weed whacker
status: publish
type: post
published: true
meta:
  _edit_last: &lsquo;1&rsquo;</p>

<h2>date: 2011-07-02 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>So we&rsquo;ve been renting a house for a bit over a year and a half.  As a techie and an obsessive tinkerer, this means an excuse to start buying tools and other things in the name of &ldquo;maintaining the house&rdquo;.</p>

<h1>How it all began</h1>


<p>One such tool which we recently bought was an electric weed whacker.  About two months ago, the weed whacker needed it&rsquo;s wire spool replaced.  In the interest of speed, I popped the plastic cover off of the spool, and removed the screw in the center of the spool (thinking it was necessary to get the spool off), all while standing in the grass.</p>

<p><em>Big Mistake</em></p>

<p>I set the plastic cover down in the grass, and put the screw right in the center of it as I replaced the spool.  Meanwhile Q is running around and playing with everything in his sight and grasp.  I should have been paying more attention to him, but I didn&rsquo;t.</p>

<p><em>Really&hellip; Really <strong>BIG</strong> mistake</em></p>

<p>When I got the new spool in, I looked down to the grass beside me expecting to grab my screw and plastic cap and reassemble the weed whacker.  But it was <em><strong>gone</strong></em>..</p>

<p>I yelled to Q and he came running, plastic cap in hand.</p>

<p>The next 30 minutes or so consisted of me interrogating the poor boy on the whereabouts of my screw, and then a futile search for it in the grass.</p>

<h1>How I became a vandal</h1>


<p>Which brings us to today.  I was in Home Depot picking up some misc. stuff, and thought I&rsquo;d try a last ditch effort to find a replacement for that screw.  Since it isn&rsquo;t a wear part, and you aren&rsquo;t supposed to remove it when replacing the wire spool, they don&rsquo;t sell a replacement.</p>

<p>Fortunately though, they DID have the exact model that I bought on display.</p>

<p><em>Do you see where this is going yet?</em></p>

<p>So here I am in a Home Depot with no available replacement for my screw, but a new weed whacker of the exact same model right in front of me.  If only I could somehow see the screw I had lost and go over to hardware to find a replacement.</p>

<p><em>So it begins</em></p>

<p>So, I casually wander over the the tool department and grab a screwdriver.  I then saunter back over to the garden center with my screwdriver in hand.</p>

<p>Watching over my shoulder, and setting Q as a lookout, I quickly remove the screw from the floor model.  Next stop, hardware.</p>

<p>With my ill gotten screw in hand I head over to the hardware department.  I identify the size and thread pitch of the screw, and grab a couple screws that match it.</p>

<p>Then it&rsquo;s back to the garden center to return the screw I &ldquo;borrowed&rdquo;, and back to the tool corral to return my screwdriver.</p>

<p><em>Mission accomplished</em></p>

<p>I am now happy to report that I now have a fully operational weed whacker again, thanks to a quick covert operation in our local Home Depot!</p>

<p><img src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5195/5896209886_a0125d52d5_d.jpg" width="500" height="282" alt="weedwacker"/></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Policy For An S3 Only Amazon Iam User]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/27/policy-for-an-s3-only-amazon-iam-user/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/27/policy-for-an-s3-only-amazon-iam-user</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>date: 2011-06-27 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>layout: post
title: Policy for an S3 only Amazon IAM User
comments: true
categories:
&ndash; Cloud computing
&ndash; Snippets
tags:
&ndash; access management
&ndash; amazon
&ndash; aws
&ndash; cloud computing
&ndash; iam
&ndash; linkedin
&ndash; policy
&ndash; s3
status: publish
type: post
published: true
meta:
  _headspace_description: A simple Amazon IAM policy to allow a user full access to</p>

<pre><code>a single S3 bucket
</code></pre>

<p>  _edit_last: &lsquo;1&rsquo;
comments: true</p>

<h2>date: 2011-06-27 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>Now that Amazon&rsquo;s Identity and Access Management (<a href="http://aws.amazon.com/iam/">IAM</a>) is more widely known, and you can use your IAM credentials to <a href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/04/04/enabling-aws-console-login-for-iam-users/">login to the AWS Console</a>, you might be wondering how to really leverage the IAM offering.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>One really good use for IAM is allowing access for specific users to specific S3 buckets.  This is what the IAM policy would look like.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>{
</span><span class='line'>  "Statement": [
</span><span class='line'>    {
</span><span class='line'>      "Action": [
</span><span class='line'>        "s3:ListAllMyBuckets"
</span><span class='line'>      ],
</span><span class='line'>      "Effect": "Allow",
</span><span class='line'>      "Resource": "arn:aws:s3:::*"
</span><span class='line'>    },
</span><span class='line'>    {
</span><span class='line'>      "Action": "s3:*",
</span><span class='line'>      "Effect": "Allow",
</span><span class='line'>      "Resource": "arn:aws:s3:::bucket_name_here"
</span><span class='line'>    },
</span><span class='line'>    {
</span><span class='line'>      "Action": "s3:*",
</span><span class='line'>      "Effect": "Allow",
</span><span class='line'>      "Resource": "arn:aws:s3:::bucket_name_here/*"
</span><span class='line'>    }
</span><span class='line'>  ]
</span><span class='line'>}</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>This contains three simple IAM statements.</p>

<ol>
<li>The s3:ListAllMyBuckets for the entirety of S3 (arn:aws:s3:::*)</li>
<li>Full control of the specified bucket (bucket_name_here, in this case)</li>
<li>Ful control of the contents of the specified bucket</li>
</ol>


<p>Sadly, there is no way to limit a user to which buckets are listed, instead you have to let them see all buckets which is accomplished by the first statement.</p>

<p>The second and third statement gives the user full control of the bucket itself, and it&rsquo;s contents respectively.  Assign this policy directly to a user, or a group that the user belongs to, and you&rsquo;re all set!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Baby]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/24/the-baby/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/24/the-baby</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>date: 2011-06-24 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>layout: post
title: The baby
comments: true
categories:
&ndash; Parenting
tags: []
status: publish
type: post
published: true
meta:
  _edit_last: &lsquo;1&rsquo;</p>

<h2>date: 2011-06-24 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/rgeyer/5630016717/" title="Tate by qwikrex, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5307/5630016717_87e53254bb_m.jpg" width="161" height="240" alt="Tate" class="alignright"/></a>
I know I have been talking soooo much about my eldest son, the amazing three year old that has accomplished sooo much in the potty training arena.  I have to say a few things about my baby boy.</p>

<p>I am in awe over this child and know that I will be trying to keep up with him for the rest of my life.  He is a climber.  Like, the kid doesn&rsquo;t walk yet (buries head in sand over the steps he ran and walked randomly) and yet he climbs everything he can get his hands on.  We like to go to a park that has the little play ground and the big play ground.  My baby boy has shown his climbing prowess by climbing the big play ground trying to keep up with his brother that is nearly 2.5 years older than him.</p>

<p>He is amazing.  Oh and he talks.  I am not the delusional parent convinced he speaks well, he is learning and is a great mimic.  He loves to try to enunciate nearly every word that he hears. <em>makes note to clean up the music listened to around him</em>  He is amazing.  Oh and he is an eater.  My first son was only interested in nursing for the first full year of his life.  My second?  He loves to chill at the BF cafe when he can but he also wants a bite of that burger his mom is eating  while nursing him.  Epic.</p>

<p>So he is &lsquo;nearly&rsquo; walking (I&rsquo;m still not willing to say otherwise), he crawls ridiculously fast, he climbs everything he can and I&rsquo;m hoping he loves a diversity of good food, so far so good. :D</p>

<p>I just adore my boys, adore.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Potty Training Day 13 No Way]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/22/potty-training-day-13-no-way/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/22/potty-training-day-13-no-way</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>date: 2011-06-22 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>layout: post
title: ! &lsquo;Potty Training Day 13:  NO WAY!&rsquo;
comments: true
categories:
&ndash; Parenting
tags: []
status: publish
type: post
published: true
meta:
  _edit_last: &lsquo;1&rsquo;</p>

<h2>date: 2011-06-22 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>He&rsquo;s being all awesome and doing all he can on his own.  I had no idea he would do so well.</p>

<p>I mean I knew he could do it but I had no idea he would just embrace the process so willingly and be so self sufficient.</p>

<p>He is awesome.</p>

<p>I am proud.</p>

<p>I officially have a giant grin on my face so big that even my baby is grinning since that is what you are supposed to do when someone uses the potty correctly.  Yay!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Potty Training Day 12 Old Hat]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/20/potty-training-day-12-old-hat/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/20/potty-training-day-12-old-hat</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>date: 2011-06-20 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>layout: post
title: ! &lsquo;Potty Training Day 12:  Old Hat&rsquo;
comments: true
categories:
&ndash; Parenting
tags: []
status: publish
type: post
published: true
meta:
  _edit_last: &lsquo;1&rsquo;</p>

<h2>date: 2011-06-20 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>We did the scariest thing ever!  We took both boys grocery shopping while one was diaperless!  Scary stuff, huh?  We went grocery shopping without both boys last week, yes we were big chickens, so what!</p>

<p>My big boy was doing well all day with the potty training, you know acting like he&rsquo;s been doing this for years.  He even had attitude with me when I asked if he needed to use the potty, he rolled his eyes and told me I was silly since he had just peed a few minutes ago.  <em>Epic</em>.</p>

<p>Back to grocery shopping.  We weren&rsquo;t used to this process and both my husband and I spaced on offering a potty break at the first store.  We went to the second store with our eldest son recovering from grocery cart regret, he didn&rsquo;t use the cart with the plastic car on the front per his request to &ldquo;Be like Mommy and Daddy&rdquo;, then lost his mind when he saw another kid riding in it.</p>

<p>So our first trip to a commercial toilet, I was nervous and my son was excited.  We ran to the bathroom since my son announced he had to pee NOW.  I saw the womens bathroom was occupied so I figured having my son with me authorized us to use the mens bathroom.  It worked out nicely and so far my son isn&rsquo;t petrified of those evil automatic flushing toilets.  We did in fact high five after washing our hands and grocery shopping was narrated by my son.</p>

<p>He is just so happy with himself but has this air to him that just says, &lsquo;Yeah, I&rsquo;m just that awesome.&rsquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Potty Training Day 11 Kicking Butt And Taking Names]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/17/potty-training-day-11-kicking-butt-and-taking-names/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/17/potty-training-day-11-kicking-butt-and-taking-names</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>date: 2011-06-17 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>layout: post
title: ! &lsquo;Potty Training Day 11:  Kicking butt and taking names&rsquo;
comments: true
categories:
&ndash; Parenting
tags: []
status: publish
type: post
published: true
meta:
  _edit_last: &lsquo;1&rsquo;</p>

<h2>date: 2011-06-17 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>Yeah, my son was a rock start today.</p>

<p>He proudly would announce that he used the potty all by himself, with a dance.  Yes, I had to escort him back to the bathroom to wash his hands and wash my own hands since I high fived him with glee before remembering that he can&rsquo;t turn the faucet on by himself.</p>

<p>Yes my son was a potty trained big boy and for the umpteenth time I have realized that my children are growing before my very eyes and it is happening way too fast but this is the wild ride I volunteered for.</p>

<p>For now I&rsquo;m just going to enjoy a song and dance with my son potty training skillZ, yeah with a capital <strong>Z</strong>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Potty Training Day 10 Getting Better]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/15/potty-training-day-10-getting-better/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/06/15/potty-training-day-10-getting-better</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>date: 2011-06-15 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>layout: post
title: ! &lsquo;Potty Training Day 10: Getting better&rsquo;
comments: true
categories:
&ndash; Parenting
tags: []
status: publish
type: post
published: true
meta:
  _edit_last: &lsquo;1&rsquo;</p>

<h2>date: 2011-06-15 00:00:00 -0700</h2>

<p>Yesterday was horrid, just horrid as everyone was struggling with the emotional turmoil of the accidents.  Yes, even the baby realized that everyone was having a hard time.  It&rsquo;s amazing how your child has an accident and you try to focus all your energy on making it right and yet you, as a mother, find the time to beat yourself up for dropping the ball and possibly not give your kid enough time and attention.</p>

<p>Today, we are getting better, much better.  My son started the day with an accident and a shower and I had a load of laundry to do before doing anything.  We followed it up with being my son then being way too confident with his bladder control and having a moment where he forgot to take his pants off while peeing.  From that point on he was showing his prowess, kicking butt and taking names and kept things dry everywhere but in the potty.</p>

<p>You are so happy you stumbled over this blog right now.  I mean, I can just see the techie followers of my husband wondering what in the hell they came across.  You can thank my ever so wonderful husband for sharing this space with his stay at home mom wife to share the joys of pees and poops and lactating boobies and other fantastical bodily functions.  Go ahead, take a minute to thank him. :-P</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
