<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Music | Random Musings]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/categories/music/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-13T18:50:29-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan J. Geyer]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@ryangeyer.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Music and the boys]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/02/02/music-and-the-boys/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-02T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/02/02/music-and-the-boys</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Both my boys seem to have interest in music, singing, drumming, and dancing.  Due to the chance meeting of my beloved and I being an affair he was DJing this is very dear to my heart.  We are a music loving household.</p>

<p>I have noticed there is a difference between the boys preferences in that baby boy is quick to join in my silliness happily and willingly.  The toddler on the other hand isn&rsquo;t a fan of my singing, my voice is pretty but nothing to write home about.  He can&rsquo;t stand my dancing unless I&rsquo;m spinning him.  Oh and he&rsquo;s not sure about my music choices when it involves me singing along.  Now that means rap is fine as I can&rsquo;t rap to save my life.</p>

<p>I had no idea that these little beings would be such critics so early on.  I am noticing that the toddler has deemed music with daddy is fine as long as he doesn&rsquo;t act too much like me when listening.</p>

<p>I can&rsquo;t wait to explain to my eldest boy that if it wasn&rsquo;t for mommy and her dancing ways he might not be here. :-P</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Music]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2010/09/14/dear-music/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2010/09/14/dear-music</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Music,</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/rgeyer/3075892157/" title="Paradigm Monitor Mini by qwikrex, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3138/3075892157_40c4001af8.jpg" width="334" height="500" alt="Paradigm Monitor Mini" class="alignright" /></a></p>

<p>First I must apologize for our lack of visits, I&rsquo;ve been so busy running around taking care of my sweet baby boys, husband and home.  I can&rsquo;t believe it&rsquo;s been so long since our last visit, you know a real  visit when we can just sit and enjoy each other&rsquo;s company.  I know we were making regular visits before my second blessing arrived and we were really making strides while I listened to my heart beat, felt my breath fall in step with you and my foot steps as I enjoyed the early morning air.  I&rsquo;m sorry for not making you a bigger priority.  I promise to make a bigger effort, after all taking the time to shut off my television and grooving and singing along with y'all makes me smile, laugh and giggle.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s amazing how a little Common, JayZ, Jill Scott, Mos Def can make me smile, shake my groove thang, and remember that life is fun to a beat.  I love it when life slows down a little more to enjoy some Sara Vaughn, Billie Holidae, Ella Fitzgerald.  Or the fun times to have pretending to be a supreme or one of Gladys' Pips, in my bouffant sequence covered day dreams.  Stevie, you just remind me of my childhood and make me want to cry while I sing along, reminding me of the good and sad times.</p>

<p>I love listening to India Arie and Erika Badu and I&rsquo;m reminded that my afro, big booty, dynamite self is fantastic and amazing.  Pink, Duffy, and even you Amy, remind me of all the angst and pain in life that is somehow is made better by a great song to sing or scream along.</p>

<p>Music, what I&rsquo;m trying to say is I miss you and I promise to visit more often.  I also promise to start the expose the baby boys to their slightly embarrassing mama trying to teach them about the joys of every kind of music she can stand, even the country music that your papa doesn&rsquo;t have to know about. ;&ndash;)</p>

<p>Thank you music and we will be talking again soon, very soon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Music]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2009/10/02/music/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2009/10/02/music</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/rgeyer/3075892157/" target="_blank"><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3138/3075892157_40c4001af8.jpg" alt="Paradigmn Mini Monitor Speaker" class="alignright"/></a>Today on my lovely morning walk I was listening to my favorite Pandora station and heard the Isley Brothers 'Footsteps in the Dark' and all that kept playing in my head is 'It was a good day' by Ice Cube.  I then recalled all the times I would get excited over a 'new' song and my mother would immediately let me know that either it was sampled from another song or a remake of a song that I should listen to.  In the beginning I would fight valiantly determined to prove that she was wrong, but in a short period of time she would prove she was right and in this process she imparted a great respect of 'older' music.</p>




<p>I have lived with many different family members which has helped form who I am in a multitude of ways.  I am in awe of how much it has formed my tastes in music.  Music is huge in all parts of my family, everyone has a passion about some genre.  One aunt insists on listening to her favorite motown or country while we eat.  My uncle and mother have a soft spot for anything Luther Vandross, the even saw him perform together.  My paternal grandmother loves gospel, and soul music.</p>




<p>The moment my husband, then fiance, went out to visit my Father's side of the family he proved himself to be a good choice when given permission to play my late grandfather's records and had most of us remembering a plethora of great memories.  He just kept choosing songs on different albums that either made us laugh while reminiscing or just look at each other with tears in our eyes knowingly.  Shortly after that My grandmother, my aunt, my father, even some of my cousins let me know that he was a good choice and he was approved.</p>




<p>I met my husband because of music.  He was the DJ at a cousin's wedding, he was cute, and he was the only single man at the venue I wasn't related to.  I asked him to dance and from the moment on both of us were twitterpated.  The moment I knew that he was something special was when he sang to me while going for a drive.  The moment I knew that he was 'the one' we were listening to the radio while watching the fire works for the fourth of July.  It is only appropriate that a dancing fool marries a DJ.</p>




<p>I love to sing, though I rarely make anyone listen.  My adorable toddler boy regularly sings along with anything and everything.  Thankfully we think we are raising yet another music lover.  Music is just such a moving wonderful thing.  I wonder just how quiet and boring life would be without music. ::shudders::  Never mind, too quiet, must search out more music.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
