<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: cycling | Random Musings]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/categories/cycling/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-08T14:35:27-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan J. Geyer]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@ryangeyer.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cycling Into the Past]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2014/12/08/cycling-into-the-past/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-08T09:15:45-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2014/12/08/cycling-into-the-past</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sunday morning I set out at 6:13 AM (a bit later than I&rsquo;d planned) for a ride
I&rsquo;d been wanting to do for some time. I had expected a good climbing challenge and
to &ldquo;put in some miles,&rdquo; but what I got was so much deeper and emotional. The
experience simultaneously told the narrative of my cycling journey, reminded me
why I ride, and transported me to long-forgotten moments in my past.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The weather was colder than forecast and I was underdressed, but that just
meant I&rsquo;d have to ride a bit harder to keep my temp up. I rode at a modest
pace to the base of Old San Marcos as the sun slowly rose. Climbing to the 154
was relatively quick and clinical. I was riding at threshold in an attempt to
set a PR and possibly determine my FTP using my fancy new power meter.</p>

<h1>Taking it all in</h1>

<p>Once I crossed the 154 and onto Painted Cave, I slowed down significantly to
recover from my previous hard effort.</p>

<p>Before too long I came across a group of folks who&rsquo;d clearly made the trip up
this mountain road to enjoy the sunrise over the city. I pondered how my solo
ascent under my own power compared to their group trek by car resulted in us
all experiencing the same natural beauty. I stopped and took a quick photo.</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/images/2014-12-08-cycling-into-the-past/VIRB0012.jpg">
<img src="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/images/2014-12-08-cycling-into-the-past/VIRB0012.jpg"
  alt="Sunrise from Painted Cave Road" title="Sunrise from Painted Cave Road"
  width="400" />
</a></p>

<p>I rode on&hellip;</p>

<p>As I approached a turnout that was a couple of twists farther down the road, I was
enveloped in an invisible cloud of a pungent and familiar aroma. As I was coming around
the next bend, a group of young adults came into view. They were leaning against
their car, flicking their lighters, and laughing jovially. I thought about how
they, too, were connecting with each other and with this place, again in their
own unique way.</p>

<p>I kept riding to the ridge&hellip;</p>

<h1>Riding into the past</h1>

<p>I reached the ridge and descended East Camino Cielo. I was officially on a route I&rsquo;d
never ridden before.</p>

<p>I crossed the 154 onto Stagecoach and descended until I reached a fork in the road.
Stopping to consult my GPS map, I realized that there were signs pointing to Cold
Springs Tavern, the direction I was headed.</p>

<p>I thought to myself, &ldquo;So that&rsquo;s where Cold Spring Tavern is! Have I been here before?&rdquo;</p>

<p>I continued descending on Stagecoach and began to detect the faint scent of an
oak campfire. As it grew stronger, and as I began to anticipate coming upon a
campsite, suddenly the Cold Spring Tavern came into view. I slowed slightly to
take in a deep breath of the aforementioned oak fire smell and to admire the
distinctly rustic tavern-in-the-woods.</p>

<p>After dwelling for a moment, I released the brake and continued descending, now
with &ldquo;Alice&rsquo;s Restaurant&rdquo; mysteriously playing on repeat in my mind.</p>

<p>Though I knew that I’d never traversed this road on my bike, I felt like this place
was very familiar, and I started to wonder why. I vaguely remembered my father bringing
me into this same Los Padres National Forest to show me the places he frequented
as a young adult. On that trip he recalled to me his memories of recovering VW-based vehicles and on-road replacement of drivetrains. His stories were colorful ones of motorcycles, camping, and the consumption of substances both pedestrian and illicit.</p>

<p>My memories of these stories, and the familiarity of my surroundings, caused my
mind to drift to a time when, as a child, my family drove up to La Honda near the San Francisco Bay Area to visit a friend of my parents. I had immediately associated the oak fire aroma of Cold Spring Tavern with one that was often present in his home, which was like a cabin in the woods. I remember his apple trees and the screams from him and my family as I nearly rolled his riding mower on the steep grade of his property.</p>

<p>Suddenly I was struck by a pang of acute sadness as I remembered that this family
friend had passed away earlier this year. Then, as quickly as that thought arrived, it
retreated, and I found myself distracted by a sign pointing out a Historical Civil
Engineering landmark, the Cold Springs Canyon Bridge.</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/images/2014-12-08-cycling-into-the-past/VIRB0017.jpg">
<img src="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/images/2014-12-08-cycling-into-the-past/VIRB0017.jpg"
  alt="Cold Springs Canyon Bridge" title="Cold Springs Canyon Bridge"
  width="400" />
</a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;d driven over the bridge probably hundreds of times never appreciating it&rsquo;s
magnitude. I thought about how before it existed, everyone would have had to drive
on the same road that I was using, climbing and descending, adding miles to their route.</p>

<p>Suddenly I was at Paradise Road before I realized that I&rsquo;d descended 1,700 feet and was consumed not by the demands of controlling my bike, but by my own thoughts and memories.</p>

<p>I stopped at the Paradise Store, which was closed. The place seemed eerily
familiar. I suddendly <em>knew</em> that I&rsquo;d been there before, but couldn’t recall when. It was like a tattered and faded sepia-tone photograph your parents show you of your house
as it looked before you were born.</p>

<p>I snapped a photo on my cell phone, sent it to the guys I usually ride with on
Sunday, and decided to turn around to head home.</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/images/2014-12-08-cycling-into-the-past/20141207_080621.jpg">
<img src="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/images/2014-12-08-cycling-into-the-past/20141207_080621.jpg"
  alt="Paradise Store Turnaround" title="Paradise Store Turnaround"
  width="400" />
</a></p>

<h1>Going back to the future</h1>

<p>As I rode back by Cold Spring Tavern I was VERY tempted to stop and share a cup
of coffee with the gentlemen sitting around the fire. But I refrained, anxious to
get back to my family whom I suddenly realized that I was missing.</p>

<p>Once across the 154 and nearly finished climbing out of the valley, I encountered
a man just waking up and stepping out of his camper. We exchanged greetings, and
I started to think about how cycling and this ride in particular had shaped my
thinking and attitude recently. When I was out riding, I was only worried about
my most basic needs like eating and drinking enough and pacing myself. I didn’t
worry about work, debt, car repairs, bills, anything else.</p>

<p>Although those things always came flooding back to my mind when I stopped riding, they&rsquo;d somehow lost some of their urgency.</p>

<p>At that moment, I was longing only to get home, have a cup of coffee, take a hot shower, have a hot meal, and enjoy the company of my wife and boys.</p>

<p>I started my descent from the ridge back toward the city. As I got closer I
encountered more cars. I found myself concentrating once more on riding, rather than my inner monologue, and realized how lost in thought I actually had been.</p>

<p>My ride that day had begun as a combination training and recreational solo adventure,
but quite unexpectedly became a journey into my past, a lesson in appreciating
my present reality, and possibly a glimpse into my future.</p>

<p>When I first started riding over a year ago, I did it for the challenge and because it afforded me
calories I could use eating and drinking things I wanted. I never expected it
to become a way to recharge and to process thoughts and feelings.</p>

<p>I found myself very much looking forward to my next mystical journey into the Los Padres National Forest on my two-wheeled aluminum and carbon time machine.</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/images/2014-12-08-cycling-into-the-past/20141207_084437.jpg">
<img src="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/images/2014-12-08-cycling-into-the-past/20141207_084437.jpg"
  alt="Los Padres National Forest Sign" title="Los Padres National Forest Sign"
  width="400" />
</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
