<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: family | Ryans Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/categories/family/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-16T22:34:00-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan J. Geyer]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moving, Moving, Done!]]></title>
    <link href="http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2009/10/13/moving-moving-done/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2009/10/13/moving-moving-done</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/rgeyer/4009626349/" title="Moving Boxes by qwikrex, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2605/4009626349_27b238c45e.jpg" width="363" height="500" alt="Moving Boxes" class="alignright" /></a>I was raised as a sort of nomad.  I have moved multiple times during my life, went to 5 elementary schools.  I was used to it.  It was always due to circumstance, trying to make a better life for the family.  I got used to being the new girl.  I just completed my third move as a married woman, my first move as a mom.</p>




<p>Let me just say, moving is for the young.  I was reminded of muscles I forgot I had and was reminded that I am definitely getting older.  Oh, and packing with a toddler is an marathon sport.  You pack, the child gets excited and unpacks you before you turn around to tape up a box.  Your habit of powering through until you are done are sanctioned by your child's needs and wants.  Just because you have 15 more boxes to pack doesn't mean that your child will willingly entertain himself for the 45 minutes you need.  Even though he usually plays by himself for an hour around that time.  Nope, your schedule has changed therefore so has your child's.</p>




<p>I have to admit I was blown away by his hysterical antics during the process.  Q has become incredibly vocal about everything.  He seems, like his parents, to have an opinion about nearly everything.  I love that he realizes now that speaking up and communicating is much more effective than screaming and whimpering.</p>




<p>I am now living in my first house in seven years, I still can't believe it.  I am simply blown away.  My son is thrilled with the space, my husband is over the moon with the garage and office space he now has.  I am just overwhelmed and kind of miss being able to see and hear everything going on in my home at all times.</p>




<p>I don't miss hearing my neighbors bathing at midnight.  I don't miss worrying about our movie being too loud for our neighbors or having a migraine and praying they don't watch a movie that night.  Parking is less of an issue, that is very exciting.  The yard is much more private, I don't always have to greet neighbors when chasing my child into the apartment.  What can I say?  I am a girl that enjoys her privacy.</p>




<p>I feel like we are entering a new era.  We were kind of hip and city dwellers when we lived in our apartment (not that we were ever really hip).  Now we are further from town and surrounded by families, minivans are everywhere out here.  Which is both comforting and terrifying.</p>




<p>Though we have some more work to do, my tired old butt would love to be done with this moving business.  So for now, today, this evening, I am sooo done!</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[But I can't juggle]]></title>
    <link href="http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2009/09/30/but-i-cant-juggle/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2009/09/30/but-i-cant-juggle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Of late the hubs and I have been trying to do everything at once.  Weaning our son, and encouraging him to sleep in his own bed.  Both of us have been crazy busy with our jobs.  We have been searching for a new home to rent.  I have been attempting to get in better shape so as to be able to keep up with a baby boy and keep my health in check to the best of my abilities.  We keep trying to keep our home clean, which seems to only last for a moment after cleaning.  Trying to really take the time to catch up with each other and making sure both of us are really getting the down time that we need.  It simply has been crazy.</p>

<p>Now we are recovering from a long weekend of attempting to do all of it, and do it well.  My son is finally sleeping for a good stretch.  It is peaceful in my home right now.</p>

<p>I just saw a LOVELY home that I want to live in but it is simply too small for our needs.  The home we looked at last night is simply bigger than we need.  I am so bummed that we can&rsquo;t make the charming little place work.  Did I mention that my husband is chomping at the bit when it comes to the larger home?  <em>sigh</em></p>

<p>I am just trying to figure out how to make everything fit in our lives and make sure nothing is being neglected.  To be a good woman, a good wife, a good mother, a good daughter, a good sister&hellip;it is a hell of a lot to juggle.  I am learning but dear lord, every time I think I have everything under control something new pops up.  I can&rsquo;t wait till the home search is done.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Loss]]></title>
    <link href="http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2009/09/08/loss/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2009/09/08/loss</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been playing on a baby board since before my precious baby boy was conceived.  I have gotten to know quite a few women on these boards over the past three years, as much as you can get to know someone on a board on the internet.  Over the past few months I have read about pregnancy losses, from a chemical pregnancies to still births and after reading every single one I am left just heartbroken.</p>

<p>Generally after reading about another e-friend loosing a child that they hoped for I close my laptop and focus on my son.  Generally when I do this I either get kisses or pushed away as I have interrupted some of his quality play time that he enjoys doing alone.  He seems perfectly happy in his own little world knowing that mom or dad are close and ready to give him our full attention when he needs it.</p>

<p>Now as I read about yet another e-friend loosing her child late in her pregnancy, I am starting to just wonder why I am so selfish.  Why am I so focused on having another child?  Why is that the ongoing monologue going on in my mind?  I am so worried about giving my precious, beautiful baby boy a sibling.  Shouldn&rsquo;t I simply happy, with the blessing that I have been bestowed by having him and leave it at one child?</p>

<p>Sigh.  Kinda makes me want to drop my over analyzing, what if&rsquo;s of having another child and just enjoy the child that I have been fortunate to have.</p>

<p>To those women that I have read and posted to in their sad time after losing that child that they had hoped to have for so long:  You amaze me in your strength.  I hope nothing but the best for you and your families, and  (((((Hugs))))).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boobies!]]></title>
    <link href="http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2009/08/30/boobies/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2009/08/30/boobies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Did I get your attention?  ;&ndash;)  Breast, boobs, ta-tas, they are a very popular topic in my household.  Not for the reason you may think, but rather because of breastfeeding.  I have been successful in nursing my child for nearly 20 months.  I have attempted to wean him for nearly 7 months.  I wish I was joking.</p>

<p>When I first began to nurse my son it was a struggle.  I learned that my failed induction, twenty hours of labor and my long recovery from my c/s slowed my milk from coming in.  I was forced to <em>gasp</em>, supplement with formula for the first couple of days home.  I was encouraged to drink beer, eat oatmeal, drink lots and lots of fluids and eat eat eat.  I was just terrified that I wouldn&rsquo;t be able to provide the food my son needed.</p>

<p>I knew there are worse things that could happen.  I knew that formula is great and it has come a long way.  But I got my natural birth taken away, I didn&rsquo;t even get to have a vaginal birth hopped up on an epidural.  So breastfeeding was one of those things that I was determined to have.</p>

<p>When the pediatrician checked our son out when he was nearly a week old and told me that he was gaining quite nicely and it was obvious my milk had finally come in.  Then he said those wonderous words, &ldquo;You don&rsquo;t need to supplement with formula anymore.&rdquo;  I was beaming and grinning from ear to ear.  I think I even made my husband repeat it to me a couple times on the way home.</p>

<p>Because my son broke out into a few pretty wide spread rashes prior to six months I was told to start removing certain things from my diet to see if it helped him.  Months later we were told that we could start adding solids to his diet but with certain provisions.  Due to the fact that I have allergies and asthma, the pediatrician told us to be cautious with dairy, eggs, berries, nuts, citrus, and strawberries.  Because we were so nervous about possible reactions I was making his food at home.</p>

<p>My son would play with the food, maybe eat a few bites but was focused on nursing.  It was like it was his favorite past time.  I felt like a failure and a success at the same time.</p>

<p>I took my son to his nine month appointment and was told to stick to the restrictions I was given but to add fat every chance I had to the solids my son ate as he was a little on the light side.  So olive oil was added to all veggies with fresh herbs.</p>

<p>We survived to his 12 month appointment and we were given the green light to start adding foods from the restricted list slowly.  I was told that he was still light and not gaining ideally but he had made a small improvement in gaining.  I was encouraged to wean him asap.</p>

<p>My son loved most foods we gave him but he was very suspicious of cows milk. I kept attempting to start slowly taking nursing sessions out and he would protest.  Most that talked to me told me to wean him cold turkey or would tell me to keep doing a good job nursing him.  My neurologist even told me to just stop nursing my son, then looked at my son and said, &ldquo;Never mind.  He is just too cute to deny.&rdquo;  Thanks.</p>

<p>So after many attempts to stop cold turkey I am now down to nursing my son only during the evening and at night.  He is not interested in a bottle, a sippy cup or pacifier at night, he only wants me.</p>

<p>I still dream of weaning my son but I just don&rsquo;t have the stamina to go through night after night of the screaming and knowing that all I have to do is let him cuddle with me and nurse.  I keep trying to distract.  I keep trying to start a new routine.  My husband has tried to be the one to put our son down for naps and for the night, he is successful for some naps and has yet to be successful for putting him down for the night.</p>

<p>We will keep trying, we won&rsquo;t give up.  We have learned a lot.  The biggest lesson we have learned is our child is as stubborn as his parents.  We don&rsquo;t give in often, he is told what he can and cannot do and those are consistent rules that are upheld all of the time.  This is the one area that neither of us seem to be able to stick to as both of us are desperate for sleep every night so that we can preform well the following day.</p>

<p>One last time, BOOBIES!  LOL!  Hey, I have to keep laughing. :&ndash;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Babies and Such]]></title>
    <link href="http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2009/08/29/babies-and-such/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://rgeyer-octopress.github.io/blog/2009/08/29/babies-and-such</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/rgeyer/3869457186/"><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2598/3869457186_2a3a0a67c6_m.jpg" class="alignleft" alt="Quincy the Thinker" /></a></p>

<p>Once you have one child often family and friends wonder when and if you will have another.  In the hubs and my case, most know that we want another child.  The debate soon after having our son, literally a couple hours after delivering our son, of who would take care of him the next time we would be in L&amp;D.   The other question that came up for the entire first year of our son's life was when we would start trying, I had hoped to wait for 4-5yrs. while my husband wanted our children closer in age 2-3yrs apart.  We had plans.</p>




<p>In my morning stupor I am starting to question our plans.  I definitely want a sibling for my son, I would love to give him one soon but I'm not sure how soon that will be.  I think I am on an information overload.  I have read so much about secondary infertility.  Too many articles about parents who got pregnant easily with their first and yet they need assistance from a reproductive endocrinologist to get pregnant with their second child.  Now I am freaking out.  What if we are one of those couples?!?  We got pregnant the first time very easily.  Are we doomed to have a long arduous road to try to give our son a sibling?  Will we be able to provide a sibling for our child?  Is now the right time to try to conceive?  Should we wait a bit more?</p>




<p>This is my own personal freak out.  Husband this is why I wake up at 6am on a Saturday morning.  I know I over think EVERYTHING but I am at a loss as to what to do and to plan for right now.  Sometimes I am such a girl sometimes, ewww.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
