<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Personal Expressions | Ryans Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/categories/personal-expressions/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-21T10:22:53-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan J. Geyer]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@ryangeyer.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time is Money - What's your hourly rate?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/02/16/time-is-money-whats-your-hourly-rate/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-16T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/02/16/time-is-money-whats-your-hourly-rate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You&rsquo;ve heard the colloquialism that &ldquo;Time is Money&rdquo; right?  Perhaps you agree, or perhaps you just scoff at the sentiment.</p>

<p>I, for one, have given this particular little proverb a good amount of though.  So much so, that I usually work out how much something will &ldquo;cost&rdquo; me for my time before I get serious about diving into it.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>See, I&rsquo;m a DIY kinda guy, I like to work on my own cars, I like to build DIY versions of retail products, etc.  But before I take something on I usually try to break down exactly what it&rsquo;ll cost me both in time and money.</p>

<h2>DIY R-Strap</h2>


<p>For those of you who may not know, I fancy myself something of an amateur photographer, and I tend to carry my dSLR around with me a lot.</p>

<p>I discovered very quickly that the standard neck camera strap is just downright cumbersome, and it often flops in front of the lens at the most inopportune times.</p>

<p>I could throw it over my neck, and under one arm.  But, I&rsquo;m a bit of a big guy too so that just results in a strap that&rsquo;s too short for me to get the camera to my eye.</p>

<p>As a result, when I discovered the <a href="http://www.blackrapid.com/product/camera-strap/rs-4/">BlackRapid R-Strap</a> I instantly fell in love.</p>

<p>Of course, being the DIY guy I am, I immediately went looking for DIY instructions for it, and I found <a href="http://www.google.com/search?sourceid=chrome&ie=UTF-8&q=diy+rstrap">plenty</a> without looking too hard.</p>

<p>Now comes the breakdown.  An RS-4 (the model that seemed most appropriate for me) costs around $60 all things considered.  Most of the DIY instructions show parts lists that add up to less than $10.</p>

<p>Sweet deal right?</p>

<p>Well, not exactly.  See, I easily spent two hours looking at all of the different DIY plans and devising my own &ldquo;best of&rdquo; from those.</p>

<p>Then, since I didn&rsquo;t have any of the parts on hand I&rsquo;d have to go to a home improvement center for the hardware, and possibly a different store to get some nylon strapping or strap from an existing bag.  Figure on another hour or so driving to and from, and wandering around.</p>

<p>Then, once I had all the materials together building my strap, testing, adjusting, rebuilding, and cleaning up could easily take another two hours.</p>

<p>Assuming that I don&rsquo;t have to drive to any other stores to buy materials I forgot, or later decided that I need to improve my design I&rsquo;ve already spent five hours.</p>

<p>$60 (Price of retail R-Strap) &ndash; $10 (Price of DIY parts) = $50 / 5hr = $10/hr</p>

<p>All told, I&rsquo;d be paying myself $10/hr to build my own R-Strap.  Then, what are the chances that I&rsquo;d end up with a product that is better (or even as good) as the mass produced, tested, and redesigned product?</p>

<p>So.. Not better, not really cheaper..</p>

<p>I bought an RS-4 from a retailer.</p>

<h2>Choosing how to spend</h2>


<p>Sometimes, you can look at a task and realize that it&rsquo;d cost you WAY less to pay someone for a particular product or service, but you still choose to do it yourself.</p>

<p>You do this usually for the non monetary benefits you receive.</p>

<p>Or, perhaps you could never hope to spare that much cash, but you&rsquo;re willing and able to spend the time.</p>

<p>For me, working on cars is where I choose to spend the time, rather than the money.</p>

<p>Sure, most times I probably take two to three times longer to fix or modify my car than a professional would, and I know I earn more hourly than the shop would charge.  But I get a sense of satisfaction in my work, the knowledge that it&rsquo;s done &ldquo;right&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Besides, working with my hands is cathartic given that I sit on my duff behind a keyboard all day.</p>

<p>Mind you, there are times that I decide that the cost of time is too great to complete a project, and I&rsquo;ll gladly pay a professional to take care of it.  This is particularly the case for the cars which we depend upon for transportation.</p>

<h2>Billable hours</h2>


<p>The other thing to consider is.  You can&rsquo;t possibly bill for your every waking hour.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;ve got the time to spare, and you can&rsquo;t monetize it, then you&rsquo;re wasting a resource if you&rsquo;re not doing something you enjoy (recreation) or being productive.</p>

<p>If you ask me, time is money in a very tangible way, so make sure you&rsquo;re making the most of both.</p>

<p>Remember, if you&rsquo;re going to spend more time on something that it&rsquo;d be worth monetarily, make sure you&rsquo;re doing it for the right reasons.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Today was a good day]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/01/05/today-was-a-good-day/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2011/01/05/today-was-a-good-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We all mark good days on different scales.  My good day may be different from yours, and I know my husband&rsquo;s good day is different from others (geeks have different definitions of most things in life).</p>

<p>Now that I am a new stay at home mom, it&rsquo;s only been six months, and have health issues and am constantly trying to keep by boys happy and healthy my definition of a good day may be different from yours.</p>

<p>My definition of a good day is only waking up twice during the night to burp and feed my baby while waking up for the day around eight.  Then both boys get cleaned, dressed and fed first thing in the morning.</p>

<p>It means getting breakfast before nine am, and drinking all my coffee by eleven am.</p>

<p>It means the dishwasher gets emptied and filled and run before lunch time.</p>

<p>It means getting some quality play time with both my boys together and separately.</p>

<p>It means a hot shower, hair styled and dressed cute.  (Oh and deodorant and lotion are a must for cute.)</p>

<p>It means we all get lunch before one pm and the mess is cleaned up shortly after we eat.</p>

<p>A good day means I get to make dinner with little interruptions and if it is from scratch that is an excellent day.</p>

<p>My good day ends with cuddles and kisses with both of my sons and some quality time with my man.  Right now, the way things went from chaotic to sweet, I&rsquo;m counting today as a good day.  I hope yours was good too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pleasin']]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2010/09/07/pleasin/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2010/09/07/pleasin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am a movie-a-holic to a degree and when Sandra Bullock&rsquo;s character in Hope Floats was told that she was so pleasin' by her mother and she told her mother she had to be pleasin' I could relate.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I spent the first 10 years of my life with my father&rsquo;s side of the family.  My grandfather was from the east coast and my grandmother is from the south.  I was encouraged to be very proper and polite due to their background.  I was three years old when sir, ma'am, and Miss were important parts of my vocabulary; thank you and may I please and excuse me were also mandatory for any conversation.  I still am notorious for getting a slight southern drawl when I speak to my father&rsquo;s side of the family and say sir to the point of annoying my husband.</p>

<p>I spent the next decade with my mother&rsquo;s side of the family, a semi traditional Mexican family.  This side encouraged me to be polite, try to make those around me to be comfortable, always try to be hospitable.  In my family we are prone to serve and be sure the men in the home are fed and taken care of before we stop and take care of ourselves.  Sadly I took on these pointers on how to be a good woman to an extreme.  I learned the hard way over and over that there is a point where you need to stop being so damn pleasing.</p>

<p>What I am starting to realize that bending over backwards on a regular basis to be pleasin' to all around me is becoming a detriment to myself.  Most don&rsquo;t completely get my limitations due to my health problems, honestly I don&rsquo;t advertise it all that much as I don&rsquo;t want people to pity me.  I&rsquo;m a strong incredible woman, though I don&rsquo;t feel that way all of the time I know it is true.  I&rsquo;m still learning my limitations, and I&rsquo;m learning where I have to put my foot down to take care of myself.  For some reason my husband seems to get this a lot better than I do.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m learning to be me but not to hurt myself in the process, I think it is time to not be so damn pleasin'.  It only took nearly thirty years for that to click.  Can you tell I&rsquo;m a bit hard headed?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Made Velveeta]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2010/08/16/i-made-velveeta/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2010/08/16/i-made-velveeta</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I attended a city college culinary program, which means I know a little about food.  I learned the basics of the culinary world, things like mother sauces, cuts of meat, basics of pastries, ect.  I&rsquo;m a foodie.  I love food, like it and love to play with it and experiment.  Thankfully my husband enjoys my experiments, eating and helping me cook and inspiring me.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Well in my attempts to focus on using on what is on hand I made a simple baked potato dinner.  Which meant I could bake potatoes and make fun toppings and have fun with it.  I decided we had to have a cheese sauce, it was vital.  I made a lovely blonde roux, then a slightly runny bechemel and then added cheeses, nutmeg, cayenne, and mustard.  It was delightful and strangely familiar.  When my husband came home after a long day he smiled as he put his potato together and let me know the cheese sauce was awesome.  He even offered to have my babies (attractive offer after you have had two children).  I looked at him and said, &ldquo;Yeah, I made velveeta.  My teachers would be proud.&rdquo;</p>

<p> I love when I get through a week when I don&rsquo;t throw away any food and we don&rsquo;t have any reason to go grocery shopping mid week, it&rsquo;s exciting to me.  Yeah I know, I&rsquo;m a bit strange.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sleep, sweet sweet sleep]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2010/08/01/sleep-sweet-sweet-sleep/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2010/08/01/sleep-sweet-sweet-sleep</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I remember being young and fighting every single nap time in preschool, daycare, and kindergarten.  I remember whimpering when my parents held true to my 8:30pm bedtime.  I just wanted to stay up and play with the adults, I didn&rsquo;t get why I had to go to bed.  I imagined that my parents were having candy and ice cream parties.  I could hear soft jazz playing in the living room and muffled conversations that had a healthy sprinkling of laughter, singing and silly noises.  I felt like I was missing out on so much.  It wasn&rsquo;t until Jr. High that I started to stay up late for school work and honestly I thought I was a grown up for not complaining.  Then high school I stayed up for cram sessions, reports, homework and started to get that sleep was a valuable commodity.  Still I would stay up Friday and Saturday in attempts to spend time with my mom and grandmother or with my friends.  I had a strict curfew, one that my mom would tell my friends and their parents so that they knew she meant business.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>One year I had insomnia, probably had something to do with the 3-5 cups of coffee that I was drinking every day in my sophomore year of high school.   I remember accidentally waking up my mom vacuuming at 1am.  She let me know that I was only allowed to do dishes, wipe down counters and dust if I insisted on staying up that late doing chores.  Clearly my mom was no fool, never tell a teenager to stop cleaning.</p>

<p>I went into a culinary program at the local city college and was in school 40 hours a week.  I got in the habit of waking up early daily (classes started at 6:30am).  I would go home and study, and have catering events at school regularly.  I was a teenager so I would also attempt to have a social life on the weekends minus the class work and catering events.  I finished the culinary program and was a baker at a buji organic grocery store so again I was keeping early hours.  I would still try to go out with friends at night even though I was up  4am to work.  I was a HUGE fan of the power nap.</p>

<p>I changed careers shortly after getting married and was getting used to 8-5 work day but still known to wake up at 3:30am often due to my previous career.  I had health issues and all I did was sleep for 6-8 hours a couple years, which for me is decadent.</p>

<p>Now I&rsquo;m a mom, with a newborn (how long do you get to claim that?) and a toddler which means that I&rsquo;m up by 7am every day and juggling everyone&rsquo;s needs and wants.  I look forward to my toddler&rsquo;s bed time on the crazy days when both boys seem to have arranged their meltdowns so I can have a stereo experience.  Then I get to play the power nap game through the night.  I miss naps, I miss long stretches of sleep.  Hell I miss sleep in general.</p>

<p>Dear Sleep,
I miss you love and know one day we will be reunited.  I&rsquo;m guessing it will be about two years but when we are together again it will be fireworks and a crescendo of beautiful music.</p>

<p>Love,
me</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
