<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Personal Expressions | Random Musings]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/categories/personal-expressions/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-16T09:34:32-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan J. Geyer]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@ryangeyer.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barbie and me]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2010/05/28/barbie-and-me/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2010/05/28/barbie-and-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My relationship with Barbie was an interesting one.  I was only given a single Black barbie, I&rsquo;m not sure if there were Latina barbies when I was little.  My Aunt (the educated career woman) made sure they had curly hair and were professionals that I could look up to.  My Aunt even took it to another level and usually bought me a book with the doll she bought me in hopes I would be more fascinated with reading than playing with the warped ideal of beauty our society encourages us to buy into at a young age.  Well done Auntie, well done.  I did get in fact get bored with that doll in a hurry and continued my love affair with books for many, many more years.</p>

<p>My mom was cool with me having different Barbies of different cultures (we rarely bought them but I inherited many from a friend that out grew all her &lsquo;baby&rsquo; toys) but said absolutely no Ken dolls.  Why?  Because they weren&rsquo;t anatomically correct and she was concerned I would be confused and frightened later on in life.</p>

<p>My mother also made sure I understood that I knew that I would never look like Barbie.  Later she was thrilled when I learned that Barbie would have to crawl to properly support her chest size as her shape was absolutely impossibility unhealthy to function with those proportions.</p>

<p>Maybe I&rsquo;m a bit of a feminist, that is debatable.  I never wanted to be Barbie as a child, I only wanted to design clothes for her and style her hair.  I mean, who else can you create fashionable dresses for out of your mismatched frilly socks?  I learned to layer my hair cuts from her which was helpful as I cut my own hair for a couple years.  I also loved to pack her van for long trips and let her chill in her house in the jacuzzi.  Sadly though I would get bored and she would at times end her relaxing soak with a blow dryer falling in the water (not my fault she was trying to multitask, I knew you weren&rsquo;t supposed to play with electronics when in water) and she would have to be carted out on a make shift gurney with a Kleenex as a sheet over her corpse.</p>

<p>Barbie for me was fun until I bought a Black Barbie that was supposed to be a Miss Universe contestant from an African country, she was expensive for me at the tender age of 12 and within a week of owning her my little sister and I were trying to see how flexible her legs were and broke one of her legs out of her torso completely.  I was upset with how shoddy it was made (obviously it had nothing to do with the fact that my sister and I were yanking on her legs like a wish bone) and swore I wouldn&rsquo;t buy anymore Barbies.  I gave all my dolls to my little sister and I don&rsquo;t think they were in our home for much longer as my sister quickly deemed them &lsquo;baby&rsquo; toys.</p>

<p>I see even today Barbie still has a strong hold on many girls interest.  Which, again, makes me thrilled that I am a mother of two boys.  It&rsquo;s less of an issue of whether or not I would let them buy these dolls and the possible impact on their self worth and self image.  Now I have to convince my boys to love that we are all beautifully made in a huge variety of shapes, colors, and sizes.</p>

<p>I guess no girl get&rsquo;s to completely stop thinking about Barbie after all.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
