<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: PC Upgrade | Random Musings]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/categories/pc-upgrade/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-08T14:35:27-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan J. Geyer]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@ryangeyer.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First 64bit PC]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2008/10/23/my-first-64bit-pc/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2008/10/23/my-first-64bit-pc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Time for the second installment of my worklog for my <a href="/2008/09/05/the-upgrade-begins/">PC Upgrade</a>.</p>

<p>Well, I actually received all the bits from UPS Monday (is it Thursday already? sheesh).  I actually assembled the thing Monday afternoon/evening, and have been slowly installing software and getting it up to speed.</p>

<p>For the curious, and so I can brag a bit heres the parts list.</p>

<ul>
        <li><a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16817104954">FSP Group SAGA+ 450R 450W ATX12V Power Supply</a></li>
    <li><a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16811119106">    COOLER MASTER Centurion 534 RC-534-KKN2-GP Black Aluminum & Mesh bezel / SECC Chassis ATX Mid Tower Computer Case</a></li>
    <li><a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16813121314">Intel BOXDP35DPM LGA 775 Intel P35 ATX Intel Motherboard - Retail</a></li>
    <li><a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16819115017">Intel Core 2 Quad Q6600 Kentsfield 2.4GHz 2 x 4MB L2 Cache LGA 775 Quad-Core Processor</a></li>
    <li>4 x 2GB = 8GB<a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16820134636"> Kingston 2GB 240-Pin DDR2 SDRAM DDR2 800 (PC2 6400)</a></li>
    <li><a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16814130378">EVGA 512-P3-N954-TR GeForce 9500 GT 512MB</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16822148288">Seagate Barracuda 7200.11 ST3500320AS 500GB 7200 RPM</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Now, this isn&rsquo;t quite bleeding edge stuff but it certainly brings me up to date and I&rsquo;m quite happy.  Because I wanted just a ROCK SOLID setup and wasn&rsquo;t intending to overclock, I went with an Intel motherboard.  I didn&rsquo;t want to regret not getting enough memory, so I maxxed it out with 8GB.  I don&rsquo;t really game so the video card is nothing special, but I did want enough horsepower to drive my big monitor and take advantage of Vista&rsquo;s Aero theme and some of the cool linux eye candy that&rsquo;s in KDE4 etc.  I am NOT disappointed!</p>

<p>So far I&rsquo;ve gotten Gentoo linux installed on the system.  The speed of compiling is admirable though not mind blowing.  One of the first things I installed though was <a href="http://cinelerra.org/">Cinelerra</a> and I loaded up some of my HDV source material.  While I should have expected as much I was able to play, edit, and render the HD in realtime!  WOO HOO!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m quite impressed with Gentoo, no hardware headaches, everything more-or-less worked out of the box.  I haven&rsquo;t quite got all my favorite apps installed and running but I trust it will be uneventful.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m in the process of moving my drives/data over from my old system.  I had a software RAID1 setup using mdadm which I&rsquo;ve been able to bring back up on the new box.  Going to play with a RAID5 since I now have enough disks, and maybe simulate a failure to test recovery.  This should get my confidence up for building a linux software based RAID5 NAS box which is the next project.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The upgrade begins]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2008/09/05/the-upgrade-begins/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ryangeyer.com/2008/09/05/the-upgrade-begins</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just placed the first of two orders for the components to my new desktop machine!</p>

<p>This upgrade is sorely overdue, the last time I got a &ldquo;new&rdquo; machine was about 3 years ago and it was antiquated then.  So I&rsquo;m going from my 2.4GHZ P4 with 1GB RAM and an assortment of various drives to this new beast I&rsquo;m building.</p>

<p>This first order was for a 24" Widescreen LCD, Ergo keyboard, speakers, and a gigabit switch.  I also ordered a power supply and some fans for an different project entirely.  The total cost shipped was $631.53 with about $50 representing stuff not associated with this upgrade.</p>

<p>The rest of the parts will consist of a 2.4GHZ Intel Core Quad Processor, 8GB RAM, a 500GB drive, Vista Ultimate 64, and a fairly run of the mill 512MB Nvidia GeForce 9500 GT.</p>

<p>Sadly, still not &ldquo;bleeding edge&rdquo; but certainly a big step up from what I&rsquo;ve got.  I&rsquo;m hoping to enjoy it&rsquo;s speed when doing stuff like non linear video editing of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HDV">HDV</a> from my camcorder using <a href="http://cinelerra.org/">Cinelerra</a>.  I&rsquo;m sure I won&rsquo;t be disappointed, and I&rsquo;ll be sure to post results here, so stay tuned for more!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
